It is with sad news... that I hereby declare... Jebediah gone, but not forgotten.
He was the first.
He laid the groundwork.
He is the giant.
On whose shoulders we shall stand today.
Let's pour one out for the homie Jebediah.
It's so sad.
He had to go in the most... horrific way as well.
Working for Clampotron.
That's just not okay.
We got Valentina.
We got Bob.
These are the followers.
And they will make us proud.
Cheers, everybody.
Guys, I'm fucking obsessed with this game.
I've been thinking about it.
I even washed my belly in preparation for this.
like I am ready.
I am locked and loaded.
I'm primed.
Holy shit, we're going to the moon today.
We're gonna go to the moon.
We're gonna land on the moon.
We're gonna... drive on the moon.
I don't even know if I can, but I'm gonna do it.
We're gonna do all the things to the moon today.
But... people... there is a problem.
And that problem is cash.
We are in dire... financial troubles.
And everything rides on this next mission.
We have to go to the moon.
And fulfill the contract.
Otherwise, this space agency...
is done for.
Everything rides on it.
It's actually kind of a tense moment.
This could... decide the whole fate.
Of the campaign.
I like it.
Yeah, let's run an ad.
Get some of that ad money.
For the Kerbal Space Program.
Actually, it's not a bad idea.
Actually, I cannot run ads.
I would do it if I could right now, before we start.
Because when I run the ads, there's like a cooldown period where you can't get ads.
You know?
But it seems like the ads have just run or something.
So I can't click on the button.
Sorry.
It is what it is.
Guys, are you...
Are you excited for this?
Like, I...
Man, I am obsessed with this game right now.
I have so many plans already.
Also...
Wait a minute.
I need to get my cheat sheet out.
For the keybinds.
I can't remember or forget that.
It's actually kind of important.
Oh god, where did I put it?
Okay, it's...
No, it's not that one.
Buttons?
No, not that one.
Oh no.
Somewhere.
It's somewhere.
I don't know where it is.
I lost it.
I'm gonna Google it real quick.
How did...
How did I...
Did I delete that file or something?
KSP, hotkey, cheat sheet...
There it is.
Oh, I know why it is.
I didn't save it.
I had it open in a browser tab last time.
That's why.
I'm gonna save it this time.
Nope.
It already exists.
Never mind.
I suck.
Had to overwrite.
Found it.
We're good.
We're back.
Okay, man.
I'm ready.
I'm so ready.
Let me activate the music.
The actual music.
Even though this is quite fitting.
Kerbal Space Program.
I did try to install the C theme mod.
You know, the dark mode mod that people suggested.
I didn't like how it looked, man.
I'm sorry.
I just wanted a dark version of the current look, you know?
That's all.
I didn't enjoy the looks of it.
So I went back to the old.
Someone also told me to potentially disable temporal anti-aliasing.
Because there was an issue with the stickers on the spacecraft or whatever.
It was flickering.
Unfortunately, if I turn off TAA, the rest of the game looks like dog shit.
So I'm not gonna turn that off.
I'm just gonna not put on the flag, I guess.
I mean, it's not a big deal, really.
But, you know.
It's okay.
Let's go over here.
So you can see what I'm doing.
We're starting.
So this was the old one.
We're at minus 7% reputation right now.
12,000 money.
Somehow I had 260,000.
But I guess it's because I didn't play on hard that time.
But, you know.
Whatever.
We can make it.
We've got a contract.
Never mind.
I forgot to uninstall C-theme.
Okay, you know what?
We're playing with it.
Fuck it.
Let's just give it a shot.
Let's give it a shot.
It just looks kind of janky to me.
You know?
Like, it looks...
I don't know.
Not good.
I guess we're playing with it on.
It's okay.
I don't want to uninstall it now.
Okay.
Let's see here.
What is the plan?
Let's look at contracts.
So we currently have this one.
This is the contract that killed Jebediah.
By the way.
Hate these people.
And for what?
8,000?
It's nothing.
This is the contract we're interested in.
Um...
Wait a minute!
Wait, we get 100,000?
For completing?
And this is extra?
Oh my god!
So we don't even have to do everything.
We just...
If we just go there...
And, like...
In the general vicinity...
We're gonna get rich.
Dude, I have a good feeling about this.
Last time, I almost hit the moon.
We just gotta go a little further ahead.
We actually got it.
It's super easy.
Let's see here.
Bum, bum, bum, bum...
Oh, it looks so weird.
So different.
Uh...
Duh, duh, duh, duh, duh.
Moon Explorer 1, I guess?
That's the one?
This is the one that actually, uh...
Almost...
Got us there.
I guess.
Something's wrong with this.
Isn't it all...
Like, it's way too...
Straight.
You know what I mean?
But it's fine.
So this one first.
This one.
That one.
Wait, no.
This one here.
Does it matter, the order?
I guess this one goes after.
Yeah, because you wanna separate and then, you know.
And this one.
And these two.
Hmm.
This doesn't feel like it's...
Like, 2,400?
Wasn't I at, like, 4,000 with this rocket?
Unless I'm...
Mixing these rockets up here.
Let me see.
Science Orbiter 1.
Oh, God.
I don't know...
I don't remember which rocket I used.
Anyway, let's just, uh...
Think about this.
So, we definitely want three stages, right?
I like this.
This is good.
And then we separate here.
And that comes home.
That's good.
That's all well and good.
And we separate there.
We have a bunch of fuel tanks.
Oh, by the way, I also unlocked something new, didn't I?
Oh, but it was...
It was too big.
No, it's not that one.
It was...
Wait, what did I unlock?
This one.
Yeah, look at this.
It's massive.
We also...
Wait, we have this one?
Oh, we have it, but we haven't bought it yet.
Okay, whatever.
That's cool, though.
Um...
Dude, I don't remember how this only had this little, uh...
Delta V on it.
This may not have been the rocket I used.
Also, if I'm going to the moon...
I was about to say, let's just put on the Science Junior.
But maybe that's too greedy, you know?
Let's not overdo it.
Let's just try and get there first.
Yeah, let's not go crazy here.
Um...
So, we have this guy.
This is a swivel.
Now...
Maybe we don't need the swivel.
We could go for this, and it's actually better.
Except that we can't steer it very well, right?
That's the problem.
Oh, wait a minute.
I remember now what I did.
I think I had full liquid, didn't I?
I was fully liquid.
Just the way that sounds is so stupid.
We need to separate this.
And...
Like that.
One more.
I can't...
Dude, let's start with Reliant, then.
Whoops.
Okay.
Looking better, at least.
Wasn't there also a way to...
Look at this?
So we had, like...
Sea level vacuum.
Ha!
If only we were in vacuum from the start, huh?
That would be nice.
No such luck.
Maybe we do four stages.
Wait.
Get rid of that.
Okay.
Dude, I have no idea how we managed to...
To get up to, like...
The insane amounts of Delta V we had last time.
Let me just see these.
This one is 12,000.
Science orbiter.
Dude, I can barely afford it.
What the hell?
Orbiter...
Science 3.
Orbiter 2?
What's that?
I don't understand.
No, it's...
It's definitely the...
Moon Explorer.
Well, shit, man.
Uh...
The thing is, we can't just launch...
Nilly Willy, right?
Uh...
Because if we fail, it's money in the drain.
But let's just think about this logically.
So we have this stage here.
That's gonna take us pretty far, right?
Then we have a...
Actually, let me change these...
Uh...
Fuel tanks here.
Instead of having all these tiny parts...
Let's have, uh...
Less parts.
But bigger parts.
Like that, you know?
That's nice.
Same up here, actually.
We can remove these.
Just make it look nicer.
And like that.
And then we can make it...
Black?
Okay.
Actually, that looks kinda cool.
I like that...
Combination of colors.
What else we got?
We got a white one.
Okay, I like that.
Da-da-da-da-da.
Mm-hmm.
That looks good.
Let me see here.
1.34 thrust-to-weight ratio.
I think that's good.
I'm happy with that.
And then the next one...
We're gonna be...
I don't know.
This is probably gonna take us up to...
I wanna say 20,000 meters.
20 kilometers.
With this one.
But we can't really turn a lot during that.
Dude, I don't understand.
Like, I have no idea what's happening.
I feel like this number should be twice what it is.
Like, I'm losing my mind.
What's happening here?
Altitude?
No idea.
I'm just gonna launch, dude.
In fact, we have two shots at this.
We have this rocket.
And then we can go again after.
Because this only costs half of our budget.
Well, shit.
Let's see here.
We put in Valentina.
Definitely, Valentina.
Jebediah is dead.
And we need a pilot for this one.
Yeah.
Okay.
Oh god, the buttons look so...
Not good.
Let's go.
Alright.
I gotta focus now.
So, speed.
SAS.
And...
Wait, I need to double check.
So this one.
Cut, cut.
And then...
Ah, wait, wait, wait.
Is that right?
Yeah, it's right.
It's right.
Okay, good.
This is actually good.
Moon, I'm coming for you.
Oh, barely getting off the pad there.
Come on, then.
Actually, I'm happy that it's going slow in the beginning.
It's not that bad, you know?
Then we can get rid of this stage earlier, and we're cooking.
Oof.
Cloudy weather.
As soon as we go to the next stage, we can start turning a little bit.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Look at that.
The cloud covers here.
Boom.
Next stage engaged.
Let's start turning a little bit.
Not too much.
Oh, oh, oh.
I don't want you to flip over or something.
Oh, my God.
It's so pretty.
I love it.
I'm going to...
Whoa!
It's starting to turn on its own now.
I don't like that.
Actually, maybe I just follow this for a little while.
Gravity should pull us slightly to the right, right?
Air resistance.
It is slightly going to the right, but I think I want to go even more.
I'm not too happy.
Valentina is focused right now.
Look at her.
Just like me.
I'm going to go a little more...
Actually, look at the map.
Look at the map.
Oh, shit.
Okay, that was that, I guess.
Uh...
All right.
So the plan is we get up here...
Man, that's not very far up, is it?
I really need to push it harder in the beginning before I start turning.
We also got to start burning a little early.
What is that?
Oh, that's the Clampatron contract.
Fuck off.
I'm not going to do it.
Or maybe I am.
Actually, wait a minute.
Take a pressure reading and fly it up.
Are we not going to be right above it?
Oh, my game just minimized.
There we go.
Um...
Actually, we should start burning now.
Horizontal.
And...
Burn.
Cheers.
Oh, my God.
It's so pretty.
We are kind of low.
Ideally...
Okay, I think the sweet spot is actually...
If you can get the top of this curve here...
It'll be right above the atmosphere.
That way you can start burning without any air resistance, right?
Look at that.
Oh, shit.
Oh, man.
I'm too late on the burn.
That's not good.
Our altitude is decreasing.
Oh, man.
At least we have a lot of fuel.
Why am I always doing it like this, man?
It's not me, I swear.
It's the rocket.
It's not my fault.
The rocket doesn't go very high.
I didn't make the rocket.
Like, I just assembled it.
Yeah, look at it.
This is terrible looking.
I feel like we should even...
Should I...
Oh, shit.
Air resistance!
Oh, crap.
Oh, you better become a circle right now.
I don't think we're going to the moon on this one.
Circle, circle.
It's coming.
Push.
Stop.
Ah, frick.
Hey, we're not losing that much speed.
In fact, we're gaining.
That's also because we're, you know, not at the lowest point yet.
This is really bad.
Which means this thing is going to be decreasing.
Apoapsis should be going down right now.
Oh, this is bad, isn't it?
How far down am I going to be?
Oh, shit.
You know what, actually?
Let's, let's, let's burn a little like this now.
I don't like where this is going.
Ah, this is fucked, isn't it?
Okay, I like that.
I like that.
Let's just...
We have to endure!
Wait, are we overheating?
Oh, no.
Please don't burn up.
It's okay.
Ah, shit.
Well, that's looking hella messy, isn't it?
Huh, radar says not much weather ahead.
Okay, altitude is increasing.
And it's still looking decent.
I mean...
This is the worst orbit ever?
Actually, I have done worse.
Let's not kid ourselves.
But it's definitely up there among the bad ones.
It's a rough start here for the Kerbal Space Program.
Joule.
Dude, I can't wait.
To go to these places.
Feels like such a faraway dream right now.
Literally.
This is quite far away.
Let's speed up a bit.
Okay, we didn't bleed off that much speed.
I don't think.
We're not in orbit yet, technically.
Because we are still below the atmosphere.
But does it matter?
Let's think about it.
Okay, so.
The moon is here.
Last time, I was sort of going like...
Here.
So I think I should go like...
Wait, where was it last time?
So I was here.
When the moon was like there.
So I think I got to go like here.
Maybe like there.
Actually, think about it.
When you accelerate to this point over here...
Remember, we were moving at 200 meters per second.
So we're going to be moving slow as hell.
If I can just move a pretty distance ahead...
We're going to be moving slow over here...
And it's just going to catch up to us.
I'm not going to catch up to the moon.
The moon is going to catch up to me.
If you think about it.
Because we're going to be moving so slow.
Last time we were at 200.
This guy is moving at 540.
Let's just...
Say like one third more...
Compared to last time.
So last time I went like here.
Let's do like...
Here.
So right here where this...
Desert launch site is.
What's happening?
Are we...
We're out of the atmosphere.
Nice.
Valentina.
Let's look out the window.
It's one of my favorite things.
You're not seeing anything...
From that angle.
Whee!
Ohoy!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay, we're...
It's out of control right now.
There we go.
Beautiful.
Okay.
Now we have a nice view of the planet.
Okay, I'm going to fast forward here.
Actually, see where the...
This...
What is that?
Map filters.
Okay.
I need to angle...
So I'm going to use this arrow as sort of indicate.
So I'm going to be like here-ish.
So it's going to be right opposite.
Now.
Maybe a bit more.
Okay, so basically we want to turn...
Uh...
Prograde.
Along our...
Velocity vector.
And...
Uh, we have so much...
We have this much fuel left.
Let's go.
Here we go, here we go, here we go.
Wait, that's...
Ah, wait, wait, that...
Uh, it's actually a little bit too...
It's going to catch up to us.
It's okay, it's okay.
I was going to say we burned too late, but...
If my theory holds, we're going to be super slow.
We're going to spend a lot of time here, right?
Remember, uh...
I don't know if you remember, but...
Fuck, what's this guy's name?
Fucking, uh...
You know...
Equal area sweep out in equal times.
Fucking, you know that dude.
Kepler.
Bup!
A little more.
Nah, it's too much, man.
I was going to go for there.
But we're going to be slow.
Actually, maybe I go a little further.
Like that.
So we're going to be even...
Actually, even more.
We're going to be even slower.
How's the inclination?
Is there a way for me to actually see stuff like that?
Like, I want to see...
I want to see...
What is this?
Moon Explorer.
Velocity.
Altitude.
Comnet.
First hop.
Kerbin.
Bicapanor?
Is this like a connection I have with, uh...
Kerbin?
Okay.
Sphere of Influence is Kerbin.
Okay, so I guess we can see here...
When it counts.
Okay.
Wait a minute.
I need to see something.
We have a lot of time before we're at the moon anyway.
I'm chilling right now.
I need to look at space travel.
Orbital definitions?
Yeah, I know what that is, but how do I see it?
Wait, there's got to be like a way to...
Docking mode.
Oh, that was the map.
Ah, here we go!
Periapsis.
Apoapsis.
But I need to see...
Oh, Advanced Orbital Info is locked?
Maybe I need to unlock something at the space center.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Approach Info locked.
Whoa!
Wait, time to reach...
Docking mode.
Dude, we don't have a lot of fuel left.
This is...
Kinda bad.
Except, check this out.
Oh, I was about to say, we are kinda low in the atmosphere here.
We're not.
But, I mean, if we just fart...
In the opposite direction of motion over here...
We're gonna be back on Kerbin.
We should be totally chilling.
You know?
Okay, let's...
Let's see.
I'm gonna fast forward now.
We need this contract.
Actually, we have one more mission in us.
Let's not forget.
There's one more mission we can do with the money we have.
So, if we fail this, we can do another.
We're moving.
Slowly but surely.
Bye-bye, Kerbin.
Oh my god, I love this view.
Look at that.
So pretty.
And the moon.
Where's the moon?
Oh, is it...
It's right next to the sun, I...
Oh, wait, wait, wait, we go...
Dude, we're gonna have an eclipse?
Look at that!
Hold on.
We need to see this.
We're speeding up time.
Oh.
Yo.
Dang.
Look at that!
Valentina, I hope you're wearing goggles.
Amazing.
Crescent sun.
Can we see the corona?
It kinda looks like we can.
But we're gonna start to catch up to it.
Let me actually see here.
So it's quite dark here now, obviously.
Can we see a shadow on the...
But I guess from my angle, it's different from the planet.
So, yeah.
Dude, it's so weird.
Let's see where we are.
Oh, we could actually make it!
Depending on how fast this moves, we could also be too far ahead.
I don't want to go too fast.
Remember last time, I sped up and I almost crashed into the earth at Mach-Million.
It does look like we're gonna overtake, but we're gonna slow down.
Oy.
Here it comes.
We're gonna spend a lot of time on this part here when it's coming towards us.
Ah, we're totally making it.
I will bet...
Everything I own...
That we're gonna make it.
Where's the moon?
Dude, I cannot see the moon.
I am so blind.
The sun is...
Making it difficult.
Look how fast it's moving compared to us.
It's faster than us right now.
We're at 430.
And also, of course, our direction.
So, this component of our velocity is gonna be much lower, right?
In fact, it's probably gonna be more like 150 or so.
Dude, this is like textbook shit.
Look at this.
Wait, are we gonna...
Hopefully we're not gonna crash into it.
Probably not, right?
Oh!
We're gonna crash into it.
We have a problem.
We have a big problem.
Uh...
Wait a sec.
I need to see this.
Dude, I cannot see the moon!
Where the fuck?
Oh, it's right there!
Look!
It's...
The sun is fucking with me.
It's coming out of the sun just like fighter pilots in World War II.
Moon is German, confirmed!
Goddamn energy fighters.
Oh, man.
Let me think.
This is awkward, because...
If I speed up along here, we're just gonna accelerate our death.
If I speed backwards...
It's not good.
If I accelerate in this direction...
That's probably what I need to do.
But that is gonna cost a lot!
That I probably don't have!
On...
Oh, wait, wait.
Actually, actually, actually.
Unless I slow down even more this way...
Maybe we can...
Oh, actually.
Yeah, yeah.
That's what we need to do.
We need to go retrograde here, bro.
That's better.
Because if we go retrograde...
We're...
We're moving this way, right?
If we slow down this way...
It's gonna curve like this.
And it's gonna be a flyby.
You ready?
Oh, fuck.
It's not working.
Uh-oh.
Actually, this is not good.
We're just slowing...
We're right now in the sphere of influence of the moon.
So the more we slow down...
The more we're just gonna come at the moon...
At a non-angle.
I guess.
Fuck.
Oh, shit.
Um...
Wait, I can't even...
Why can't I move the spacecraft?
Ah!
Why can't I...
Turn it?
What's happening?
Turn that off.
Oh, my God.
We're fucked?
What's happening here?
Oh!
Okay!
I mean, flyby the moon!
We did that!
Wait, gather scientific data?
Uh...
I guess crew report?
In space high over the moon.
What kind of geologic...
Geologic formation is that?
Well...
Don't worry about it.
Uh...
Shit, bro.
I...
Does that work?
It doesn't work!
It doesn't count.
Unless it only counts when you bring it back.
Because we technically haven't...
Oh, I don't know, actually.
But wait, we have to return.
Oh, let me...
I need to think about this.
So wait, right now...
Right now, just forget about Kerbin, honestly.
This is a moon...
Vessel...
Uh...
Physics system right now, right?
And right now, we are on a direct collision course.
I think, honestly, we need to...
Burn this way.
Yeah.
It's the only way.
It's not great.
We don't have fuel for it, but...
I don't know why I can't turn the spacecraft, though.
That's, like, the problem.
If I click here...
Oh, now it works!
Why are you not able to...
Command.
Control.
Wheel authority is 100%.
Reaction wheels are running.
I must have done something.
Maybe that matters?
Ah, okay, okay.
It was because I was in the wrong mode.
Uh, okay, so we need to see here.
This one...
Is what?
Show me the moon.
Oh, it's gonna be in the sun again, isn't it?
That bastard.
Show me the thing here.
So I guess I wanna do...
Oh, it's kinda weird, because we're not in orbit right now.
We're going straight into the...
Frickin' moon here.
Maybe I'll just do it on looks.
I'm gonna do it...
I'm gonna fuckin' eyeball it.
It's that one.
Actually, I'm not sure what that is.
I like this one more.
I like this configuration right here.
This is good.
Wish me luck.
Not bad!
Not bad at all!
I'm gonna assume the moon has no atmosphere, so we should be okay going quite close to it, maybe?
Okay, so we are gonna pass by here.
In fact, the moon is gonna slow us down slightly, which probably means we're gonna crash into the Earth when we come back, when we leave the sphere of influence here.
Not bad, man!
Ho ho ho ho!
We still have fuel left.
Okay, you know what?
Let's celebrate.
Look at Valentina!
We're going on an EVA.
Uh, yes.
It's EVA time.
Uh, we're gonna let go.
I wish I could see the moon more, man.
It's right there.
You can't see it, because the frickin' sun is outshining it.
This is, by the way, the problem of finding exoplanets.
You know?
The host star is always so bright that you usually can't see planets among, you know, orbiting other stars.
So what you do is, you wait for it to actually move in front of the star so that the total light output, you know, is going down.
That's how you...
or that's how you at least used to find exoplanets.
They probably have more advanced techniques nowadays.
But that's one of the first ones they used.
RCS.
Whee!
Why are we turning like that?
Wait, what's happening?
I'm not doing anything.
Uh...
I... I'm not pressing my keyboard.
Why is she turning?
Stop!
Is my shit malfunctioning?
Oh, maybe we're okay.
Oh, god.
SAS?
Wait, what's the difference?
Oh, it doesn't go towards camera.
Oh, my god.
It's so weird to control.
I have to get used to this.
How do I get up again?
Alright, right.
Down.
Left.
SAS.
Okay.
Let's do EVA report.
While in space, high over the moon.
Entering the dark side of the moon and losing contact with mission control makes you realize just how isolated you are from the rest of your kind.
But we're not on the dark side.
Yet.
9.6 science?
That's pretty good.
All things considered.
Wow.
Look at the moon.
I know.
There's the hatch.
Grab.
Let's get in.
Okay.
So, if we trust the orbit right now, we should not hit the moon.
We should be flying right by it.
I'm gonna speed up slightly.
Man, the moon is being shy.
It doesn't want to show its face.
We've yet to see it up close.
It's gonna be a jump scare when we get there.
I'm moving at 50x right now.
Let me actually go in here.
Turn around.
There it is.
You can see the...
Whoa.
The outline of it barely there.
See that?
Kind of hard to control.
There we go.
I really should connect, like, a joystick or something.
I thought about it the first stream, but I kind of forgot.
Time is moving faster.
Here we go.
Faster.
Oh, wow!
Slow down, slow down.
Oh, my God.
Dude, I fucking love this.
Look at that.
Wow.
The Terminator.
Turn off the UI there.
Dude.
This is me with my Nikon in there, you know, taking pictures.
Sending it back to Mission Control.
Dude, we're getting pretty close here.
Dude, it looks so good.
Jesus.
Let's turn it around.
Slightly.
There we go.
Oh, my God.
Let's try something here.
I want to see if we can...
Damn.
Man, the sense of scale is just not the same in third person as it is from inside the capsule, is it?
I mean, it's still there, and it still looks amazing.
But from inside that capsule, man, you can just kind of feel it.
Okay.
I'm gonna do a crew report.
Overwrite.
It's still space-high over the moon.
Okay.
Canyons look like scars across the moon's face, which is appropriate considering how much the moon has survived millennia after millennia.
Yeah.
Not a lot of geologic activity on the surface of the moon here.
It's geologically dead.
That's why there's so many scars on it.
That's a lot of craters.
We're gonna be walking on that moon today.
We're going on the moon.
Okay, so...
We have some fuel left here.
We have to be careful.
Let's speed up time.
Whoa.
What's happening here?
What is that?
A big boulder, I guess.
It looked weird.
I can just look at this forever.
Oh, man.
That's so cool.
Trust that the orbit is correct here, and we're not gonna...
freaking succumb.
You know what?
Let's get a cool angle here.
I want to try this.
That's not that cool.
Goddamn window has patterns on it.
Okay, we've been sightseeing enough.
Let's speed up...
Whoa!
Damn!
Holy shit, wait a minute.
We have not been sightseeing enough.
Oh my god.
Oh my goodness.
I mean, that's just...
Earthrise right there.
That's the picture.
That is the picture, man.
It actually looks very similar, doesn't it?
To the real thing.
So cool.
Valentina.
Are you excited?
Oh, she's cool as a cucumber.
Same color, too.
Bye-bye, moon.
It was nice knowing ya.
So I know you can plant flags in this game.
I can't wait to do that.
We're gonna get on the surface and plant the flag.
Let's see here.
Okay, we're gonna be at an awkward angle here, it seems.
There we go.
Oh, I don't actually like this very much.
Mission time is one day and two hours.
I think what we have to do, we have to get to apoapsis, burn retrograde, and let periapsis fall into the atmosphere.
I think that's our best bet at efficiency here.
You always want to burn opposite of where you want to increase or decrease the elevation, right?
So we're gonna have to take a trip around the earth.
Or carbon, I mean.
You saw the moon is behind the carbon now.
I like that I called it the carbon, like we say the earth.
Why do we even say the earth and not just earth?
If you think about it, it's weird.
What's wrong with us?
Okay, let's get over here.
Speeding up like crazy now.
I don't want to go too fast, because accidents happen.
Okay, now we point retrograde.
Beautiful.
And then...
Oh wait, I can also look here, I guess.
Maneuver mode.
160 kilometers.
Let's bring it to...
58, I guess?
Maybe slightly less.
We'll see how that goes.
We're gonna be coming in hot, man.
This may actually be...
a little scary.
Nah.
That's probably fine.
We'll see.
It depends on the angle, I guess.
If we flip over, it's game over, but...
Uh, let's see.
Shall we?
Now, be careful with the speed controls, man.
One...
at a time here.
100x.
Look how slow we're moving, man.
133.6.
1000.
I'm scared to click again.
Maybe I quickly click and go back.
Okay, it's not that bad.
Slow down, slow down, slow down, slow down.
We're gonna speed up, remember?
Slow down.
Oh, I'm coming home.
And we've got the juice.
I hope.
Dude, I don't know.
Why isn't this, uh...
Recover or transmit any science experiment data from the moon to achieve this goal.
I guess it's just because I haven't actually technically recovered it yet.
Because I gotta get home with it, right?
I hope that's what that means.
In any case, we're gonna get paid for each of these.
So even if I don't get this one done, we're gonna get the paycheck.
So I'm happy with that.
And here we come.
God, this planet is beautiful.
It truly is.
We're already at 2,000 meters per second.
Oh, I like that it's automatically, uh...
It's holding retrograde.
As soon as I go back to 1x on speed.
So I guess this doesn't work when you're at speeds above 1x.
That makes sense, I guess.
Uh-oh.
Oh, I don't like that we're going on the dark side here.
But I think we're gonna pop out...
In a good spot here.
Going a little faster.
So dark.
It says 160,000, but...
I'm still afraid of hitting a mountain or something.
Because I can't see anything.
I know that's not gonna happen, but...
That's what I'm thinking.
Oh, I should also, uh...
So periapsis 56.
Maybe I should burn a little more, just to be safe.
Use up all the fuel, maybe.
That's probably fine.
I mean, we're gonna be slowing down quite a bit.
I'm gonna detach.
You ready?
Damn.
Okay.
We're at 70-ish...
Kilometers.
Okay, we're at 1x now.
Oh, man.
It's already starting to heat.
This thing is, too.
This thing will overtake us, because it's gonna become like a missile.
And it's gonna fly ahead of us.
When we get down.
I'm afraid of fast-forwarding.
Imagine if you do this, and you forget the heat shield.
You're just like, oh, wait, shit.
I guess we're dead.
God damn.
Please let us pop out on the bright side.
None of this darkness crap.
Come on.
We're not slowing down a lot.
But...
Look at this thing.
I mean, we're...
If we don't slow it down enough, we're gonna come back around.
Slower than before, right?
Oh, my God.
I can't see nothing.
Okay.
Yeah, we're starting to exit the atmosphere again.
We did not slow down enough.
I knew I should have burned more.
Damn it.
But hey, maybe this is actually a good thing.
Because this means we're not gonna come in as steep.
You know, and we bleed off some energy now.
The next time we come back around, it's not gonna be as crazy.
This may actually be kinda smart.
I'm gonna speed up.
I can't go more than four.
There's the moon.
Planets.
Yeah, now we're back in space.
Oh, man.
I'm sorry, Valentina.
Your dinner's gonna have to wait a little longer.
She's been underway almost a week.
Look, it's six days now, mission time.
Why can't I go faster?
Oh, now it works.
Hundreds.
Weeeee!
Careful now.
I think these lines are my connections.
Okay, we're still very far.
Well, you could see, like, altitude in this view.
Can I?
Somehow?
Maybe I can't.
Like, I don't need this right here.
I need altitude.
How far down are we?
Hundred kilometers.
Just wait a bit.
So, around 70 is when we enter.
And the needle will start moving on atmosphere.
There.
See?
This time we're a little slower.
I'm gonna speed up, man.
This is a crazy return trip.
Okay, I learned my lesson, though.
When you wanna return home, you gotta go to less than...
57 kilometers.
Yeah, see, now we're starting to exit again.
Are you kidding me?
Okay, we're gonna have to do this a couple times, I guess.
But I think we're gonna go home safe.
Sorry, Valentina.
Lunch is gonna wait.
Yeah, we have to skip dinner.
Oh, I think it's maybe when you're in space.
Then you can do it.
For some reason, you have to go back.
And then go back up.
It's kinda weird.
50x.
Hundred.
Whee!
Back we go.
And I guess now is the atmosphere.
It's already doing it automatically.
It's actually kinda nice.
Here we go again!
This time we're at 2,600 meters per second.
Dude, how many times are we gonna have to do this?
We're at 4x now.
We're bleeding off so little every time.
Why did I...
You know what?
I shouldn't have disregarded my engines.
Or, like, disconnected them.
I still had some fuel left.
But I guess I couldn't have known.
Hmm.
I mean, look at this over here.
Hey, you know what?
I actually think we're gonna get home on this side.
We are actually gonna end up home on the bright side of the planet.
It sounds ridiculous, but it's true.
Because we're not gonna slow down over here anytime soon.
Okay, so when we hit 70, we can start to do this.
Dude, again?
Look at that!
Well, I guess chances of when you go in the same plane...
...of seeing it happen is kinda high, I guess.
I can't believe it.
Another eclipse.
Valentina has been on a journey, man.
This has been an adventure.
You see how the, uh...
...the lines here shift depending on where you are?
This is how we maintain connection with, uh...
...the space center.
There's different ones around the globe.
That's actually so cool.
Let's see if this is enough.
2,400.
Think about it.
The slower we move...
...uh, the more time we spend in the atmosphere.
But of course, the faster you move, uh...
...uh, the more drag matters.
I think it goes by the velocity square.
So I don't actually know which one of those two terms matter most.
In this case.
Well, we'll find out.
Oh, we're slowing down a lot now.
I guess we came a little further down this time, so...
...the air is more dense.
Yeah, look at that!
Look!
You see that?
Oh, we're totally coming down now.
This is it!
Hold on to your hats and goggles!
I'm gonna go 1x on this.
We're finally coming home!
There we go.
Don't even need to look at the UI.
Now Jesus takes the wheel, you know?
Also, what happened to my...
...stage?
It's not that back there.
That's me.
I wonder where it is.
It's probably off somewhere else.
Oh, yeah.
Wait, let me actually look at the heat shield.
Oh, look at this!
It's actually kind of low.
Ah, we'll make it, right?
We've gone past this planet so many times now, there's surely enough for this one.
Should be okay.
So I wonder if this actually means that as long as you have a blader left, you can survive any heat.
Or maybe there's like a maximum heat for this heat shield and you can get a better heat shield.
You know?
I guess it means...
I think it's the first.
That would make the most sense.
I don't want to land on the dark side, man!
Fuck!
After this trip?
That's so sad.
Actually, this was so textbook in a way.
The way we came home here.
I mean, except the, you know, skipping across the atmosphere a couple times.
Ignoring that, I think it went pretty dang well.
Where are we?
In the middle of nowhere.
Valentina, you're probably going to have to wait a couple more weeks in this capsule in the middle of nowhere for the rescue team.
I'm sorry.
Shoots!
The drogues are up.
I think we can safely deploy...
The main chute as well.
I think we're going to hit the...
Hey!
We're not going to splash down.
We're going to hit the ground here.
Nice.
At least her snacks are going to stay dry.
There they go.
This ambient light.
Where is this coming from?
Why is the ground so visible?
What is that white stuff?
Is there any right below me?
We have to investigate this at some point.
Because this is a mystery.
Like, what are these things?
Scattered all over.
I can't see anything out the window.
It still hasn't said anything.
Maybe when we land.
Let's pay attention.
Wait, it says 200 meters.
Is this...
Oh, it's got to be, like, sea level.
Return...
Uh-oh.
Let's see.
22.8 signs earned.
Nice.
We got all of this back.
Two experience gains!
I mean...
I better...
Okay, we need to see this now.
First, warp to sunrise.
So we can actually get some light.
Oh.
Brief shower.
There we go.
Oh, that's so much better.
Okay.
Mission control.
Hey!
Oh, wait.
Did we actually do it, then?
Or did we just do it partially?
Yeah!
Okay, so it does mean...
You've got to bring it back.
Nice.
Okay.
So, wait.
How much money do we have?
Oh, 300,000!
We are saved!
The space program is active!
We are so active!
Let's see here.
What...
Rescue Carson from orbit of Kerman!
I mean, Kerman.
As a consequence of the somewhat worse than average accident at Research and Development Department, we've been forced to look for some outside help.
We've been performing a lot of experiments with leaving Kerbals in space for extended periods of time.
Things were going great until Carson woke up and decided to walk out of their capsule.
This is where you come in.
Say what?
Rescue Carson Kerman, who is stranded in low Kerbin orbit.
Return him safely to Kerbals!
No way!
That actually sounds like a lot of fun!
Whoa!
I like that!
Science data from space around the moon?
Oh, that's going to be an easy one now!
Are you kidding me?
I've got that one in the back!
Science data from the surface of the moon!
That's going to be a little more tricky, I think.
I don't even think we have the parts for this.
Like, do we even have landing legs or...
You know, a lander module or whatever?
Mmm.
I don't think we do, man.
I shouldn't take this yet.
Let's see what else we got.
Bring Moonstone back with you!
Explore the moon!
Go to the moon and stay there in a nice stable orbit.
It isn't personal, it's science.
Oh!
You know what?
Let's do that one.
Guys?
Fuck Clampatron.
I'm going to cancel this contract.
Yes, we're going to lose some money, but I don't care.
They killed Jebediah.
Fuck him.
I want Explore the Moon.
30,000 is respectable.
Boom.
And then we're going to take...
Wait, what's the difference between this one...
And that one?
This one is way worse.
Oh!
Wait, oh!
Oh, it's Kerbin.
I thought...
For some reason, I thought it was Moon.
Never mind, never mind.
It's me.
I suck.
Okay, uh...
I guess we take this one too?
Dude, the next mission is going to be orbiting the Moon!
Getting scientific data.
Taking photographs of the surface.
Finding a suitable landing spot.
Oh, my God.
We got two contracts now.
I'm going to need to save the game, bro.
Imagine we crash now and everything's gone.
Ho-ho-y!
Not on my watch.
Okay.
So we are actually kind of flush with money.
And we have 50 science.
Can I even spend it on anything?
I can!
Ooh!
I can't buy any of this, though.
Oh, we can also buy these parts now!
Do we even need these parts?
We don't need the parts.
Okay, so this one is mega huge, right?
We need a fuel engine.
Or a liquid fuel engine that is big enough for that.
It's probably going to be this one, isn't it?
Frick.
Shit.
Maybe I'll take this one.
It's only 18.
Radial decoupler?
That sounds nice.
And nose cones?
Oh, yeah.
I'll take this.
I mean, I'm rich.
Now we have 32.
Not enough for the next stage, unfortunately.
But that's okay.
This is fine.
I mean, I already have what I need to go to the moon.
We've already proved that.
Not only that, we can probably improve on that design, too.
So let's do it.
Oh, my God.
The moon explorer one was insane.
The next one is going to call moon...
orbiter...
extra...
Actually, no, no.
We're going to call this one...
Jebediah.
And his name.
He died.
Trying to please...
clamp...
Oh.
Tron.
Yeah.
That's it.
Save it.
This is the Jebediah.
Let's make it...
perfect.
And I mean...
Ideally, we want to bring a scientist.
Maybe Bob is the man for this mission.
Bob has proven himself again and again.
He's done it on Kerbin.
He can do it on the moon.
Let's actually buy these.
I'm rich, man.
I can afford it.
Thanks.
I take it.
Oh!
Look at this one!
I wish I could see the size of it, but...
Oh, maybe I can.
Do I have, like, a...
radius?
Which size is this?
Will it fit?
That's what she said.
Okay, I bought these.
Let me see.
Oh!
It's too big!
Ooh!
It's perfect!
Oh my god!
Christmas come early!
This is just getting straighter and straighter and...
longer and longer.
Like, I mean...
I guess that's one way to make rockets.
Not bad!
I like it.
I actually do like it.
I like it a lot.
Let's see these ones.
Is this too big?
I can't tell.
Is it too big?
Oh, it's too big!
No!
Why is it too big?
What's this one?
That's way too big!
Mega big!
Uh, wait, let me actually check all...
Oh, wait, wait.
Oh, wait a sec.
Hmm!
Maybe we can afford not to be super aerodynamic?
I actually kinda like.
Oh!
Oh my god!
That's it!
Holy shit!
Wait.
Is this even a good engine?
Wait a minute.
374?
Dude!
That's insane.
374 at sea level.
ISP is also pretty good.
It's like a good engine.
It's a good engine.
But this one.
600.
Holy crap.
This one is made for space.
Sea level is terrible.
High ISP.
And vacuum.
Uh, you know what?
I'm actually...
I'm gonna stick to this very straight.
Thin rocket.
It's like a pencil.
Um...
Which fits, I guess, with Jebediah.
I mean, that's his nickname, you know, for reasons.
That only some Kerbalites know.
Just saying.
But, uh, it fits.
I'm gonna make this a little tinier.
Because we have a lot of speed here now, right?
We don't need to bring...
In fact, check this out.
Maybe we can do only two stages.
Is that crazy?
Maybe it's crazy.
I mean, okay.
Check it out.
If the last rocket got us on a flyby, this will for sure take us in an orbit.
Right?
Boom.
It's as simple as that.
And this time, we're gonna bring science instruments.
That's right.
Ah, but wait a minute.
Coming back down with that is gonna be troublesome.
Remember when...
I think it was with Bob.
We were in orbit around Kerbin.
We did some experiments.
We tried to come back.
But the shape of the re-entry capsule was super weird.
And we even lost some of the science.
It exploded on the way down.
Maybe this is where we need to start investing in antennas.
You know?
So we can transmit it instead.
We have a high-gain antenna.
I wonder if that means we can then get more science value.
Variance.
Radial axial?
Oh, that's cool.
Oh, that's dope.
Hmm.
I feel like we should just go.
We bring Bob.
Oh, wait.
Science.
So what do we do about science?
Tolerance.
Uh.
I guess what I used to do last time was...
This one.
So tolerance.
It can tolerate 14 meters per second impact.
Which is actually kind of crazy.
Because usually we hit the ground at about 6 or 7.
I swear I wasn't trying to make like a joke there.
But we actually do hit the ground at around 6 or 7 meters per second.
And it can take up to 2,900 Kelvin.
I'm not sure what that means.
But let's see the capsule.
Capsule.
Oh, see that one is 2,200 Kelvin.
Okay, what about the...
Uh.
Oh, God.
3,300.
Oh.
So there is a max temperature.
It's not just about how much ablator there is.
Okay, that's actually good to know.
Very good.
Interesting.
There's three variants?
I didn't even notice.
How does that look?
Oh!
I like it being black.
Looks cool.
Neat.
But, I guess we don't want to do that right now.
Because we want to put it on some science.
Ah, it'll be fine.
If we just take this one.
And then we disregard the science junior again.
Like we did that one time.
I like that strategy.
So, science...
No.
First we take...
Oh, I need to figure out this UI here.
So here...
No.
Yes.
And then...
Then the heat shield.
Like that.
And then we do this.
And then the science.
And then inside of here...
We're gonna put things.
I'm gonna put it in there.
This one we need, of course.
So wait.
Double keybinds for this.
One, two, three, four.
Rotate.
Can I rotate in like...
Snapping manners?
90 degree...
Somehow.
I don't know if I can do that.
That works.
Oh no.
What the...
Ah, what have I done?
Wait, how did I just...
I have no idea what I just did.
Move tool.
God, this is so fucking...
I...
Okay.
I gotta be honest, man.
The building mode is...
Not good.
It's not.
This is janky as hell.
Not working well.
How the fuck...
How do I connect this, man?
Like that?
And then here?
Now it won't...
What's happening, bro?
Okay, delete this.
Hate it.
Put a new one.
See, now it works.
It doesn't make any sense.
Rotate.
Christ.
You know what I'll do?
Check it out.
We're gonna...
Cancel this.
Give me...
Science Orbiter.
Because I already did this once.
See that?
It's in there.
Boom.
And I'm gonna adjust the rest.
Get rid of that.
And then put on...
That one.
Okay.
See, all of this is actually pretty good already.
We already have this too.
That's nice.
Looking pretty nice.
This one can be made even better.
We can put in...
Some of these instead.
Give them some color.
Or remove color.
Heh heh.
You know.
Is that...
Is that an engine?
It is.
Get rid of that.
And...
Maybe we do one more.
It's a bit of a long one.
It's a long boy.
Orange and...
Black.
There.
Huh?
Oh, maybe one more...
This connector.
Oh, we also have this now.
Oh, wait a sec.
Wait a minute.
Wait.
We can do a booster on each side.
And then push them off.
Yo.
That sounds pretty...
But do we even need it?
I mean, we have this bad boy.
What about two of these bad boys?
That's maybe too much.
I think this is good.
Like, this is a good rocket.
Solid rocket.
This is the last...
Second to last stage.
Let me see.
So this one goes off first.
Disconnect.
And this goes with it here.
Dis...
Wait, what?
Yeah, that's wrong.
This goes here.
This one goes away.
Activate.
Wait, what?
There we go.
No.
Hold on.
Something's wrong here.
Oh!
Right.
That's an engine.
So if that's an engine...
What am I doing with this?
Hello?
What is wrong with me?
This is the engine there.
And then we have these two.
Yeah.
There we go.
Then this one goes here.
Disconnect.
Activate.
And then this one gets...
Activated.
Parachute.
Yeah.
I think this is it.
We got it.
Yo, let me actually try something here.
Can I bring more than one?
Crew capacity is one on these.
Okay.
Dumb idea, but check it.
Wait, this may be a really dumb idea.
How do I...
That's terrible.
Wait, wait, wait.
Unless...
Can I like...
Oh, wait.
This is too big anyway.
Ah, shit.
Okay.
You know what?
Fuck.
I gotta...
I gotta take a pilot.
I just remembered.
If we come home at that speed...
Man, we need to...
We need to have some control.
You know?
We can't have Bob at the controls.
I'm sorry, Bob.
I know you did well last time, but...
I just don't trust you.
I really don't.
This is good.
I think we got it.
And now we need to call this...
Jebediah.
He died.
For Clamp.
O.
Tron.
Save.
Overwrite.
I think we're ready.
This is gonna be as smooth as butter mission.
Like, you've never seen anything as smooth as this.
What?
Wait, wait, wait.
There we go.
It's gonna be so easy, actually.
Valentina?
Again.
Oh, this is probably her experience meter.
Orbit around carbon 2.
Fly by the moon 2?
Wait, these numbers don't make sense.
This ain't true.
She only flew by once.
What's going on with this?
Those stats are not correct.
Unless I'm totally off the mark here.
Let's go.
Okay, so we have contracts.
Orbit the moon.
Easy.
Transmit or recover scientific data from space around the moon.
Easy, easy, easy.
Woohoo, you ready?
Wait, wait, wait.
Did I put heat shield?
Can I...
Did I put a heat shield?
Yeah.
Otherwise, why would this be here, you know?
There's a heat shield.
We got it.
Okay.
Man, that... Actually, now that I look at it on the pad, it doesn't look as long.
It is a long boy, but it looks like a proper rocket.
Speed.
Sass.
And... Liftoff of Jebediah in search of science orbiting the moon.
This is in honor of Jebediah.
So you know what that means, right?
We're gonna crash and burn.
Ah!
We're not gonna crash and burn.
Valentina is at the controls.
It's gonna be fine.
I'm not even sure if this rocket booster is giving me anything that I didn't have before.
It doesn't feel like I'm gaining more... Like, yes, it has more fuel in it.
And yes, it has more power.
But are those just gonna cancel each other out and I'm gonna end up at the same height?
I'm not sure.
I'm gonna start turning slightly, actually, if I can.
Okay, we're definitely getting more height, I think, compared to before.
Yeah, we're going quite fast already.
Okay, this booster has a lot of juice.
Never mind, I take it back.
This thing is crazy powerful.
Get ready for stage!
Boom!
Now we start turning.
Because I didn't get the opportunity earlier, so we're gonna turn aggressively here.
Uh-oh, we're rotating.
That's okay.
Okay.
It's like a sausage on the grill.
You gotta rotate it.
Roll program.
Let me see the arc.
Oh, shit!
That's very...
Go horizontal.
Dude, there's a lot of juice in this rocket.
Holy crap, bro!
I guesstimate that's about 90,000 meters.
Watch me be right.
I don't want to fire this engine yet, actually.
Boom.
Goodbye, sir.
Dude, this is...
So much easier with that booster!
Holy crap!
This is insane.
Okay, so now, next stage...
Um...
Go a little higher up.
I'm not gonna start burning too late.
I'm gonna start...
Now.
Right now.
This is it.
Maybe I started burning too early.
We'll see.
I don't think so.
I think this is perfect.
Let me look at this now.
Maneuver mode.
That is looking clean, ladies and gentlemen.
So far, at least.
I think I did start to burn a little too early, but that's okay.
Get it, like, there.
So finicky with the SAS.
In fact, I can just wait a little bit until I'm higher up.
And then, as soon as I'm at the top...
Well, almost at the top.
We're not burning directly prograde.
We're burning along the ground.
What's the height?
Oh, 140?
I was totally off at my estimate.
I thought this was, like, 90.
Yes.
Very good.
Right there.
Let's stop at...
100.
Boom.
Beautiful.
Absolutely beautiful.
Not bad at all.
Okay, so the moon is there.
So last time...
Actually, I should look from straight up.
I think I went, like...
So it's, like...
So if this is 90, it's, like, here.
What is that?
Like 75-ish?
Which means it's, like, there.
Okay, now we...
Wait a bit.
Oh, wait.
The moon is moving as we do this.
Ah, it's not moving a lot, actually.
It's fine.
Okay, so, like...
There.
Beautiful.
Start burning.
Prograde.
Just another day at the office for Valentina here.
Easy peasy.
Lemon squeezy.
I got a little off course there.
Because I started rotating like a...
Like a madman.
Uh-oh.
We're going a...
Our inclination is a little fucked up because we did that maneuver.
It's okay, though.
Slow down a bit.
Oh, you know what, actually?
I just had a genius idea.
Point retrograde.
As long as I burn...
So, like, there...
We will never hit...
Let me think.
Actually, it depends on the moment's trajectory.
Isn't this...
What we had before?
Maybe we went a little further this time than last time?
Okay, so now we just wait.
Looking decent.
Look at that.
Time for a high five.
It's going to start catching up to us because we're so slow over here.
Oh, look at that!
Fucking beautiful.
There's the...
Kerbin.
Damn sun is blocking the moon again.
Okay, so now we want to get to periapsis here, which is at 70 kilometers.
And then we burn retrograde to stabilize the orbit.
Right now we are on an escape trajectory.
We're going to be close to the moon here.
Yeah.
This music is just so fitting.
God damn, man.
I can't stop looking at it.
And you know what?
In real life, if you were to look this way, the sun would be way worse than what it is here.
Like, you cannot be looking at the sun.
I mean, not even on Earth you can.
It's a bad idea.
Don't look at the sun!
Okay, here we go.
There's Kerbin.
Where's the moon?
Oh, there it is.
I somehow looked in every direction except the moon.
Here we go.
That's an orbit right there.
I'm actually going to conserve fuel.
I'm not going to burn more.
We are now locked to the moon forever if we were to do nothing.
Well, I guess there's maybe some dust in the air at times or in the space around here.
So maybe over thousands of years we could be slowing down slightly.
But, you know, if we don't do anything, Valentina will stay here indefinitely.
Okay, so now we are definitely in the space around the moon.
So let's do some science.
We're going to do material study.
Oh, this is going to be insane amounts of science, right?
Over the moon.
30 science!
Oh my god!
Okay, transmitting is only 10.5?
Or maybe that's because I don't have a...
Actually, I forgot to put that on.
Yeah, I don't have, like, an antenna.
We're going to have to try and experiment with that.
It's getting very difficult to keep track of your experiments as they float around in the low gravity.
Maybe you shouldn't have tried to...
Them all at once?
What's that mean?
Something wrong there.
Okay, let's open this.
Oh my god, let's go spacewalk.
Man, that is...
Pretty.
Look at that.
Oh!
This game is amazing.
Let go.
Wait a minute.
I guess technically what I could do...
Wait.
Let's say I were to just burn with my jetpack.
Like, in one direction here.
I can...
I can adjust my orbit with just my...
With just my curveball.
That's kind of fucked up.
Uh...
I guess if you had enough fuel, you could technically land on the moon with a jetpack, if you think about it.
No, fuck.
I would...
I keep thinking...
S is going down.
W is forward.
There we go.
Mystery goo.
Let's see what the goo does next to the moon.
Oh, I didn't click on it.
Observation can only be externally controlled by a scientist.
Oh, shit.
So I just go inside.
Or...
Doesn't seem like a problem?
Uh...
EVA report.
No science at all.
As you carry out your EVA, you feel your nose get progressively itchier.
The resulting sneeze almost spins you out of control.
Doesn't make much sense, because the snot is not going anywhere, is it?
It's just moving around the helmet.
I guess it would add a little spin.
No, it wouldn't.
It wouldn't, actually.
I'm trying to think.
Let's say you have a helmet on.
You're completely still in space.
You sneeze.
Snot comes out of your nose.
Lands on the...
On the visor.
I feel like it would spin you initially, and then it wouldn't.
Actually, I'm not sure.
That's a tricky physics question.
I can't think about that right now.
Anyway, reset that.
And go inside again.
Let's go.
Just back.
Oh, it's so weird being...
No.
Small corrections is the key when you're doing this.
Okay, let's do crew report.
Man, also nothing.
I guess because I did it last time?
Let's try and see if we can run these now.
Yes.
12 signs is insane.
The goo has eaten your snack!
What part of do not touch did it not understand?
Well, Valentina...
She's used to not getting any food, isn't she?
A temperature scan.
Measuring the temperature of space appears to be quite impossible, as there's no matter around to be either hot or cold.
Yeah, yeah.
And then we have barometer.
It reads zero.
Dude, we get 14 for that!
I guess it's because of this.
That's all it is.
That's crazy.
Oh, wait.
I need to do something here.
I need to go grab the science from this.
If I even can.
I don't know if I can, because I'm not a scientist.
Small corrections.
Collect data.
Nice!
And then...
Beautiful!
And I cannot do this.
Because I'm not a scientist.
Okay.
I can close the doors.
Wonderful.
Trying to think what else I can do.
Oh, this is so sick, dude.
Valentina...
Looks extremely happy...
To be spacewalking.
Maybe that was a dream of hers, ever since she was a little...
Kerbal.
I'm hearing yelling.
Wait.
Oh, it's kids outside playing.
For a second, I thought the Kerbal made noises.
Close this.
I guess our job here is done.
Well, this one's not going to be activated until we come back home.
So, now we have to come home!
Let's not forget that part.
Now I'm trying to think.
Where would you...
I guess if I...
So we're currently...
Like...
If we think of the moon and the spacecraft as being one vessel right now, we are of course orbiting Kerban.
So if I exit this way, it's going to slow me down on this path over here, which means it's going to make me...
I'm going to have to spend less fuel getting back.
Whereas if I exit the gravity of the moon this way, I'm going to add to the already existing speed of, you know, going around this way.
So basically, what I'm saying is, we would like to ideally burn over here and then get out that way.
But since the shape of the orbit is this way, I think here is good.
Then again.
If we burn right now, we're sort of going this way.
No, actually, right now we're burning...
Yeah.
We're going to have to...
We're going to be on the other side.
We don't have a lot of fuel, actually.
This...
It's a little scary.
But then again, the moon is not very...
Massive.
So hopefully, it's not going to take a lot of fuel.
I'm a little bit nervous.
I'm not going to lie.
This is not looking too great.
Ah, but let's not forget...
No.
Let's forget.
Right.
So if I...
So we're going...
Actually...
Oh, actually, it's better to burn on this side when we're over here.
Yeah.
Does that make sense?
No, it's actually better to burn over here while we're here right now.
So we just got to go to the other side.
But the thing is, we're moving quite far in the orbit.
Fuck it.
We're going to burn here.
It should be fine.
What the...
Is the moon right in front of Kerbin?
Wait, what am I looking at?
No, that can't be right.
Oh, I'm an idiot.
What am I even saying?
It's the Kerbin in front of the sun.
Dude, what are with these alignments today?
What is happening?
How is this like...
Isn't this like super...
Unlikely?
That I keep getting these crazy views.
Wow.
Prograde, go.
Jesus.
And look, there's no sun on us right now.
That's so cool.
Alright, let's escape this, shall we?
Really?
We need more?
Dude, how much do we need?
I feel like I fucked up here.
No, it's okay.
It's okay.
We're actually chilling.
I'm almost using no fuel for this.
I'm at like 1%.
Okay, let's take it from here.
Bye-bye, Moon.
Thank you for the science.
I will never forget it.
Okay, so now we're gonna...
There we go.
And I am a lazy bitch, guys.
I'm gonna start burning retrograde right now.
Don't care what anyone says.
I feel like Valentina has suffered enough.
So last time we were at 57.
Let's try...
40.
40!
And I think I will...
Should I keep my engine?
Kind of...
Dude, I kind of want to get rid of it.
But let's...
Let's wait a bit more.
God, man.
The views.
Look at that!
Ooh!
It's tickling me.
Here we go.
Don't speed up too fast!
Oh my gosh.
I am so nervous with the time warp.
Okay, 100x is good.
100x is good.
Whoa!
Actually, we're not even that fast right now.
2,500.
But we're gonna speed up, of course, when we reach here.
Okay.
I guess we can...
Should I burn even more?
Just to guarantee that we don't do another go-around?
Yeah, fuck it.
There we go.
Maybe a bit more.
That's cool!
This is it!
I'm gonna disengage.
I mean, dislocate.
I mean...
What's it called?
Uh...
Stage...
You...
I don't know what it's called.
There's a word for that.
I'm doing it.
Bye-bye, science...
Department...
Module thingy.
See ya.
Okay, now we have to be careful, because we now have a weird shape here.
But we do have SAS.
So it should be okay.
The assist will help us.
We're at 200,000 meters.
We're only gonna start heating up at around 70 kilometers.
So I can safely just do this.
Let me calm down a bit.
80...
Let's get ready.
Atmosphere is happening.
Very soon.
Parachutes are primed.
Ready for action.
What if I accidentally activate Parachute now?
I guess that's bad.
But wait, if we're in space, I wonder if I could go outside and pack the parachute back in.
Before we hit the atmosphere.
See, now it's too late, I guess.
But, you know...
Theoretically, I guess...
You could.
3,100.
And we're coming in kind of steep.
But look at this.
No problem.
There goes my stage.
Uh-oh, I don't like this meter here.
Nah, it's not going up.
We're chilling.
I think.
I mean, I can't do anything anyway.
Let's just enjoy the cinematic here.
Cheers.
God, that's so gorgeous.
Okay, I would say we come in at a pretty good angle.
This is very nice.
This is very shallow.
Oh!
Oh my god.
Imagine the game crashed.
That's scary.
Ooh, I think we did it.
Slowing down.
Science intact.
Wonderful.
And then it's time for the drogue chutes.
Let's do that at 15 kilometers.
Deployed!
Oh, and it's nice and bright.
And look at the views.
Now, this is a return trip.
This is what I like to see.
None of that darkness crap.
In fact, where are we on the globe here?
Somewhere random.
Would be cool to, you know, get back to the actual launch pad.
That is kind of badass if you manage to do that.
Main chute.
Deploy.
Man, what a mission.
And in Jebediah's honor as well.
Whoa.
I'm assuming that lightning cannot kill me.
Or, like, fuck me up.
Imagine coming home after that and then just getting struck by lightning.
That would suck, majorly.
There we go.
Main chute is deployed fully.
And now we're just descending.
Success is coming in.
I think we did everything.
Yeah, look at the flag.
It's, like, flickering.
That's annoying.
Not if I get close, though.
Looks like a seafighting issue or something.
It's probably too close to the actual model.
model.
Where, you know, the renderer has trouble deciding which one to show.
Gah!
Was that the heat shield?
I mean...
Not bad.
Going out with a bang here.
Um...
There was something we didn't do earlier.
Review data.
No, this one is good.
What was it?
Can't click on that thing.
That one's good.
Oh my god.
We get so much science from this?
Wow.
Crew report.
Hey!
You imagine how hot it would be if the capsule did not have the AC on.
It would probably be very hot.
Uh...
Let's just recover, man.
Let's take our win.
That was a beautiful mission.
Exactly everything according to plan.
It was actually textbook.
76 science earned.
Wow.
Oh, guys.
We...
We came back from the brink of complete annihilation here.
This space...
This space program was hanging on by a thread.
But now...
Oh, I think we're going into fuel systems.
Are we?
Maybe we're not.
Aviation.
Oh, airplanes.
Uh...
Am I crazy?
I'm not excited about airplanes at all.
I want to make rockets, dude.
Flight control could be nice, though.
I mean, reaction wheels?
Depending on how useful they actually are?
What's all this?
It's the next step in unmanned control technology.
Oh.
Rechargeable battery...
So, hold on a minute.
Batteries.
I need to try and understand what the point is of batteries.
I haven't actually encountered any issues...
Where battery, uh...
You know, matters.
Yet.
I'll have to think about that.
A spotlight.
Oh.
A dome light.
Illuminating a small area around your craft...
And can be spotted from far away.
Okay.
But, dude.
I gotta say.
I'm excited by...
This.
I want fuel tanks.
I want to connect it to those new...
Uh...
Boosters I got.
Or...
Engines.
Right?
Advancements towards a better understanding of how fuel flows through a rocket.
Yes.
We're going with this.
Ooh.
63,000.
But I do have 411,000.
Let's not buy them yet, actually.
We're only gonna buy the ones we need.
Yeah.
That's good.
Now, mission control.
Oh, we did both of these.
That is just phenomenal.
Plant flag on the moon.
Conduct temperatures...
Don't...
Oh, man.
Yes.
Wait.
There's gotta be something I can unlock that gives me, like, legs.
Strut connector.
Maybe?
Mobility enhancer?
Scanning arm.
Wait, what...
What even is that?
Wait, EVA fuel cylinders?
How much fuel do I have?
Default.
Oh, my God.
Antennas?
I can't look at it.
I'm gonna get overwhelmed.
I'm too excited.
Okay, I'm gonna look at it.
I'm not gonna look at it.
Because I don't have signs anyway to buy it.
So, fuck it.
Right?
Oh, but wait.
We have 411,000?
Maybe we can upgrade something here.
That's way too expensive.
This one we can upgrade.
Patched conics visible in map.
What does that mean?
I mean, I know what patched conics is, but...
How does that...
Visible in map?
900 is way too...
Steep for me.
Fuck that one.
Don't care about that one.
Max active contract 7.
Oh.
That could actually be pretty good.
Tracking station upgrade required for flight planning.
So, wait.
If I get this and I get this, I get flight planning?
Or what?
What does that mean?
How does it work?
Ah, but 300...
Ah, we're totally chilling, right?
We're gonna have 100,000 left.
I'm gonna do it.
Whoa, look at that.
Cool.
Flight planning available?
Okay.
This is the next thing we're buying.
Let's take contracts.
Everything's about the moon now.
They know I can do it, so they're like...
Okay.
Now you gotta go do a lot of stuff on the moon.
Plant flag on the moon.
Rescue Carson from orbit of Kerbin.
Ah.
Maybe we can try this.
We've been doing a lot of moon stuff.
We can maybe try something at home.
Rescue Carson Kerman.
Who is stranded in low Kerbin orbit.
Return him safely to Kerbin.
The problem I have, though, is...
Let's say I were to get up there.
And I put him in a capsule.
There's not gonna be enough room for two people.
Right?
Because I only have a capsule with one space.
So maybe I need to research something that gives me more.
Where did I see that?
I saw something at some point.
Is it down here?
That one.
For crew capacity.
But that's actually not the one I was thinking of.
That was something else.
That one.
Hey, I could...
I could not get this.
Never mind.
Command.
Electrics.
Oh!
Whoa!
Oh my god!
Lander can!
Mooner excursion module?
Yo, my...
Oh my god.
Okay, we...
We gotta go...
We gotta go via here.
Oh my god, it's a lot.
It's 45, 90, and then 160.
Oh!
I can't afford that!
Not yet!
Okay, we...
We...
We can't do this contract.
Unless...
On...
Wait, I actually have an idea.
Wait a minute.
I need to test something.
Save this.
Make a new.
This is gonna be really dumb.
But watch.
What if...
Wait a minute.
Look at my cheat sheet.
Uh, VAB...
Move...
Rotate.
Yes.
It's like one of those things you have at bars when they mix drinks, you know?
Like a measuring cup.
Okay.
But wait.
Where does the parachute go?
Wait.
Would this even work?
I'm trying to think.
If we put some weight on one side...
Say...
Well, I don't know.
But...
Something.
Something weighty.
Why...
Why won't this...
Wait.
How come it's not...
Snapping to that?
I guess it doesn't matter.
We can use either side for this.
Wait.
Is this...
Is this redonkulous what I'm doing?
I feel like I'm doing something that's horrible.
I feel like this is maybe a bad idea.
I don't know.
I need to think.
Ah, wait.
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
This is gonna look so dumb.
But you gotta trust me, okay?
Because we need to be aerodynamic up front.
When we go up.
And then we even get this.
But wait.
Then we don't need this?
Oh, wait a sec.
Oh my god, I'm a genius.
That's it?
This is the shape.
That I saw in my dreams.
This is it.
Why can't I click on it now?
Bro, I don't understand this system.
Okay, I...
I guess this is the shape we're going with.
What?
Accidentally, uh, alt-tap there.
Uh...
I don't know why I just got scared like that.
I think we just do it like this, guys.
Ah, but wait.
Wait, then this is going to be the hefty part.
It's going to weigh a lot.
Also, wait a minute.
We also have to think about how do we even...
If someone is up there in orbit, we're going to have to do a rendezvous.
That's...
That's what, uh...
They did on the Gemini...
Actually, was it Gemini or Apollo?
I think on the Apollo missions, they had to...
practice how to do rendezvous, because they had to, you know...
bring vessels together and fly them close to each other in space.
We have to think about that as well.
Hold on.
This is actually a multi-problem...
uh...
problem here.
Like, a multi-step problem.
There are multiple issues with this...
plan here.
But I have...
I have faith.
Uh...
Maybe we can even improve on this.
Wait, maybe there's other ways to do this.
So let me think.
Crew capacity is one on this one.
What's...
Why is this good?
I get...
Okay, it survives way more...
heat.
It's not way more, but somewhat more.
Okay.
Okay, okay, check it out.
I have it, I have it.
We're gonna start with this.
Right?
And then...
Oh god, it's ugly.
This looks like one of those pieces you use in a board game.
You know what I mean?
I don't like this.
I don't like what I'm doing here.
I actually hate it.
I...
What am I doing?
Wait.
Why am I thinking one-dimensionally?
Wait, it's the same design.
What?
Oh, oh, oh.
Ah, but there's no crew seats in this.
It's a pro...
Bodo Bodine Stay Putnik.
Hmm.
Okay, real question.
Can I not...
Wait.
Real shit?
Wait a sec.
What if I were to EVA inside of here?
Close it.
And then come back to Earth?
Think about it.
I mean, it sounds redonkulous.
But it's a game.
You know?
So, hold on a minute.
This part has...
Uh...
Some stats, right?
Tolerances.
I wonder what the tolerances are for a Kerbal.
I can't see those stats.
That's the problem.
Hmm.
Batteries.
Ah, man.
Here's the thing, though.
Why would they give me the contract if I'm not able to do it?
I think I am able to do it with what I have.
I just need to crack the code here.
You know what I mean?
I think I was onto something with the shaker.
How?
Oh.
There you go.
Like, this is the design.
You know?
Maybe.
And I...
Okay.
Hmm.
I wonder what the most aerodynamic...
You know, configuration is when this falls through the atmosphere.
It's probably gonna be along here.
No.
Actually, it's not.
I think it's gonna be one of these sides here.
And I'm gonna put a heat shield on.
This is actually...
We're gonna do this.
No flags.
This is an undercover operation.
And...
At the end, we're gonna have...
Oh my god.
This one.
Turn it.
Oh my god, it's beautiful!
Make it black.
Oh, that's...
Oh, that's beautiful.
Yes!
And then one is...
Oh...
No, no, no.
I don't like that, actually.
Fully black.
Full black.
Nice.
And now...
Decoupler.
And then...
I guess we...
He's low carbon orbit, right?
So that's not even hard to get up to.
That should be fine.
That's like easy mode.
Um...
Okay, you know what, actually?
Why am I hyper-fixating on this?
We don't need to do this now.
I'm gonna wait.
I clearly don't...
I don't have a plan.
I just thought about how I'm even gonna meet him up there.
And I already got like, whoa.
Okay.
Let's just not do it.
We're gonna wait with that.
But at least I already put some thought into it now for later.
You know?
When we finally get to it.
That's the plan.
Okay.
So let's, uh...
Let's do the moon, I guess.
Let's try...
To...
Um...
Science data from space around.
Kerbin.
Guys?
I'm fucking doing it!
I don't know what else...
I'm gonna do it.
Shaker is coming in.
It's coming in hot.
It's happening.
Heat shield that shit.
Make him black.
You heard it here first.
This is happening.
I have an idea.
And now...
Tanks.
Like that.
And then...
We're also gonna add...
Uh...
One more tank.
A smaller one.
That one.
That is so pretty!
Oh my god.
Look at this.
This even has color too.
Okay.
We can't...
Color that outside one apparently.
But that's okay.
Oh my god.
It...
Not only is this functional...
It's actually beautiful.
It is.
Oh wait.
I have a great idea.
Uh...
It's actually wonderful.
Wait.
How much does this weigh?
0.03 tons.
And the heat shield?
It's gotta weigh more.
Uh...
Yeah.
It weighs more.
Oh wait.
It's this one.
0....
Wait.
Yeah.
It weighs 10 times more.
So...
Oh but wait.
So if I come in...
Let's say I come in through the atmosphere.
The heat builds up here.
It's gonna go around there.
Yeah.
This is fine.
We're gonna be protected I think.
It is a little unsure.
I will admit that.
This is an unsure...
Situation.
But it's fine.
Now we need parachutes.
I guess we're gonna have to go with the radial ones.
Wait.
No no.
Yeah.
Radial ones.
Oh they're big.
Look how big these...
What?
Why are they so big?
Like a massive one.
0.1.
Oh these weigh less.
Huh.
So I guess we wanna put the heavy ones at the bottom here.
And the non-heavy ones...
On the top.
This is actually genius dude.
Actually put them further down.
Like that.
Just so they don't get hit by...
The heat forces.
You know?
Oh it's beautiful.
Okay.
Nice.
And then down here we're gonna have an engine.
Boom.
Decouple.
Decouple and...
Uh...
Well we're just...
Okay so wait.
We're probably gonna have to do a bunch of maneuvers and fuckery up there.
So let's just bring extra fuel.
These are my thoughts.
Do three here.
I like my swivel.
I like it.
I'm a fan of the swivel.
Let me see what else I can do.
Can I make it look cooler?
You know what?
I like it.
What about this one up here?
Can we make that look cool?
Huh.
Alright.
I mean I like that.
That's fine.
Now.
Ah but wait.
Then this doesn't work.
Hmm.
I see.
Now for a booster.
And I think we're going with the big boy.
That's too big.
We just need a thumper for this one.
Ah.
Uh.
1.15 is very low.
Let me get rid of one of these tanks.
In fact.
That's fine.
I guess this weighs a lot up here.
Huh.
Can I color this one?
Oh.
It's beautiful.
Dude I love this rocket.
I'm in love with it.
Turn these white.
This one doesn't have different colors.
Also.
We got some new um.
Look at these.
Oh they're big.
Boom.
Dude.
That actually looks sexy as hell.
No.
Actually I don't like it.
It's ugly.
I like these better.
And we save money.
I actually hate these.
It's fine.
Okay.
Oh wait wait.
Uh.
We're gonna call this uh.
The.
Kerbal.
Rescue unit.
Also called the crew.
Leave.
No.
Kerbal.
Is it Kerbal?
Or Kerbal.
I guess it Kerbal.
Behind.
Leave no Kerbal behind.
Save.
Okay.
I need to see this uh.
Contract now.
Low Kerbal orbit.
Dude.
We're gonna get 40,000 just for this?
That's so worth.
Yes.
So wait.
Uh.
How do I know where he is?
Can I see him?
Oh.
Well there you go.
85 kilometers up.
Sweet.
Oh yeah.
Okay.
Sounds good.
Uh.
So the basic idea is uh.
You can.
Okay.
So what I'm thinking is you can be at different altitudes right?
And if you have an orbit there you're either gonna move faster or slower depending on the elevation.
You know.
So we just need to catch up or let him catch up to us.
And then minor corrections I guess?
It sounds easy but it's probably harder than it sounds.
Uh.
Wait.
Is he?
I need to see something.
Okay.
He's moving.
This way.
I just needed to check.
Would be weird if he was moving the other way.
Uh.
Here we go.
Let's check everything.
So first stage here.
Separate.
This comes in here.
Put that there.
Put that...
Wait.
Which one is which?
These are the drogues.
So they go here.
I'm actually a little worried about this.
These parachutes are big.
I'm gonna move them slightly up.
Maybe I can even be a little naughty here.
Actually I shouldn't do that because maybe they won't deploy them.
You know.
Because of geometry.
Let's not fuck with that.
Don't fuck with parachutes.
That's like a very important rule I guess.
Alright.
I think we're ready.
Let's go.
Wish me luck.
We're going on a rescue operation.
Trip.
I'm a little worried about this shape up here.
We'll see how this goes on the way up.
Wait a second.
Oh, I was about to say.
Yeah, we only...
Wait a sec.
I hope the game didn't auto put someone in the other capsule.
I don't know if I can see this here.
Recover vessel.
Hold on.
I need to go back.
I need to just double check.
Because I think I want to put Valentina in the bottom one.
Because this one is more likely to explode.
So, you know, I want to keep my Valentina.
Which one is...
Which?
How do I know?
Dude, I'm...
I don't know how I know.
Okay, I have an idea.
I have an idea.
We look out the window and see if it's upside down.
If it's not upside down, then she's in the top one.
Okay.
She's in the bottom one.
So, this top one is empty.
Good.
Are we ready?
God, I hope this is actually going to fly fine.
Looking good so far.
Looking very good, in fact.
These two.
That one.
Yep.
Beautiful.
Let me start turning slightly.
Because I can feel the ship moving left.
Oh.
There we go.
Oh, that sounds nice.
I like the sound of that engine.
That's nice.
I'm going to try and...
Instead of, like, making big arcing turns, I'm going to slowly turn all the way, you know?
Like a smooth curve.
It feels aerodynamic.
It doesn't feel too different than the other rockets.
I'm not too worried about the front.
The shaker setup here is not a problem, it seems.
Time for the next stage.
Wait, this is actually not good.
I'm very low already.
Hey, look!
He's right there!
Dude, we're going to catch him right now.
Get to him!
Get him!
Can I click on him?
Set his target!
Carson's debris.
Here we go, here we go.
I'm coming for ya!
Point towards Vector here, at least.
I should just prograde it.
Actually, we should be moving faster, of course.
Wait a minute.
Oh, he's a tooth.
He's going to catch up to us.
That's good, though.
That's good.
I mean, this is not the way to do it, but...
It could be.
Could be the way to do it.
Wait, target position at...
What did that say?
Target position at Intersect 1?
Intersect 1.
Separation...
60 kilometers.
Wait, what's happening?
Target position at Intersect 2.
Wait, hold on.
Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on, stop, stop!
Pause!
Let me see if I can find something about this.
What does that mean?
I guess I would look for...
Map Interface?
Oh, here it is.
When looking at orbits, there are a number of helpful indicators.
Ascending, descending node...
Intersect markers.
These show where you will be closest to your target.
The downward marker shows where the active vessel will be.
And the upward one, the target's position at the same time.
Okay, but why are there two sets?
Okay, so wait, hold on.
The downward marker shows where the active vessel will be.
So that's me.
And the upward one, the target's position at the same time.
Okay.
So, so, at this time, I'm gonna be here, and he's gonna be there.
Wait, let me try and speed up a bit.
Target position... Wait, let me actually... move more like this way.
Now, there's no way I can catch up to him, though.
Also, I'm using a lot of fuel here.
Dude, we're kinda close.
Hey, look, we're exactly... oh.
Intersect two.
Whoa.
Wait, intersect one.
Am I crazy?
Do I... No.
If I accelerate up to be on the same height as him, I'm not gonna catch up to him, because we're moving at the same speed, then.
So, that's not gonna work.
Um... but I'm gonna have to burn here anyway... to get into orbit.
That's gotta be, like... the first thing, right?
In fact, I'm actually a little higher up than him, so he's gonna... move faster than me.
So, I will never catch up to him.
But... eventually, he's gonna catch up to me.
Right?
Uh... be horizontal there.
What do you do?
My fuel is...
We're not having a lot of fuel.
Actually, maybe we do.
We let him catch up to us.
It's fine.
Oh, look.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Look.
Hold on.
They're moving closer.
I can't see it.
Separation 0.3 kilometers.
Okay.
So, that's good.
Then we're gonna be there.
And we're not gonna be in the atmosphere, right?
No, we're at 92 kilometers.
In fact, maybe I can even do...
Oh!
Gave it too much.
Burned the opposite way now.
Clicked wrong.
Shit.
I don't know what I just did.
Uh-oh.
There's an intersect over here.
But that's not gonna help.
Or maybe it is.
This is...
I feel like I'm not doing this right.
This feels...
Janky.
Like...
Something's off about this.
Feels like I'm trying to hack something.
You know what I mean?
Okay, wait a minute.
These are moving.
Actually, kind of a cool way to display it here.
And boom.
3.3 kilometers.
Okay, but wait.
So, let's say...
Wait a minute.
So, let's say we get there.
And the...
And...
We're gonna be within 3.3 kilometers of each other.
What then?
Oh, wait.
Target.
Oh, shit!
I can actually see it!
For some reason, I just...
I don't know.
I imagine we were, like, instanced or something.
Where it wouldn't actually show this.
You know, like, for gameplay reasons or whatever.
And then when we would get there, we would be put in the same...
Do you know what I mean by this?
That's awesome!
Okay, so wait.
We get close to each other.
I guess I just start burning towards them so that my...
Velocity is pointing at them.
Right?
That seems pretty simple.
Hold on.
Since we have some time...
Let me actually read this again.
Orbit nodes continued.
Active vessel.
Future patch.
Moon adds sphere of influence change.
No, that's not interesting.
Not right now.
Maneuver nodes.
This map tool is arguably the most important tool for getting to your chosen destination.
With it, you can plan the location, direction, and orientation of a burn.
What?
Simply left-click anywhere on your orbital path, the actual orbit, or future paths after existing maneuver nodes.
What the fuck?
Oh, we can set an alarm for that.
I don't want to do that, actually.
Oh, periapsis is in four...
Oh, that's funny.
So you can set an alarm for when we're at periapsis.
Ah!
That's neat.
I don't need to do that, though.
Maybe this is what I need to unlock with the flight planning thing.
You know?
Maybe that's why I can't do it.
That's probably what it is.
Wait, I was looking...
What was I looking for?
I already forgot.
Fuck.
I was looking for...
I don't know what I was looking for, actually.
I forgot.
Turning with gravity.
Aircraft basics.
No, I don't care about that right now.
Flight interface.
Navball.
Oh, yeah.
Man, I really...
Hmm.
Shows intercept information if a target is selected.
Oh, I guess...
Wait, dogging mode?
Maybe.
You could see it as a way of me trying to dog with them.
Oh, cool.
Okay, so this is just a way to show...
Uh, exactly when we're gonna be at closest intersect.
So in 10 minutes, we're gonna be 3.2 kilometers away.
And obviously, we're gonna start drifting apart again.
It's a fleeting moment.
Man, we had it at 0.3, remember?
And I had a misclicked.
Fuck.
Shit.
That's such a blunder, actually.
We may not have enough fuel for this.
I...
We don't have any more fuel than this right now.
This is it.
Unless we can...
Also, wait a minute.
How do I get...
I have so many questions already.
Like, how do I get him in?
Hold on.
There's gotta be something about this.
Docking mode.
Toggle.
Space bar.
Toggle's between translate and rotate.
Okay.
Whoa.
Okay, I can't look at that now.
Cargo app?
What the...
Dude, this game is massive.
Yeah, this...
What?
I don't...
Okay.
Let's just fucking wing it.
How hard can it be?
He's right there, dude!
So I should point my vessel...
I should turn around like that, so that I point at him.
Let me see.
Oh, that's too much.
Wait.
Wait, is this...
Is that pointing towards him?
Yep.
And my current vector is here.
So ideally, we want this to be right there, because velocity, we gotta put it in the direction of the target, right?
But, uh...
Maybe not yet.
We wait until we're close.
3.3.
Also, why is the music gone?
Uh-oh.
We are gonna start slowing down.
Going through the atmosphere here.
And slowing down means we're probably gonna drift apart slightly.
Wait, what?
Oh, did I set a...
Alarm?
I didn't mean to.
Delete.
Whoops.
Okay.
Here we go.
I'm moving faster than him, because I'm in a lower orbit.
But I'm also in the atmosphere.
Here...
Well, barely.
Let's see if this actually changes as time goes on.
Oh my god.
I wish I could just...
It's very...
Janky, man.
Like, the mouse registration here is just not...
There we go.
Yeah, 3.4.
You see that?
Shit.
The problem I have here is fuel.
That's a really...
But the good news is we're already in an orbit that is going to eventually de-orbit us, you know?
3.4.
How far is he away from me now?
20 kilometers.
Okay.
So if you think about it logically...
We are currently pointing in this direction with our velocity vector.
So that way.
Which means we need to burn here.
To offset that.
Well, you could burn anywhere.
It just depends on how much.
Here we go.
Moving closer.
3.4 separation.
Oh, it also shows we're going to have a relative speed of 76 meters per second.
Okay.
But I guess that...
So if it's positive, I guess that means...
I'm faster than...
Him?
Yeah, because right now I am faster than him.
Yeah, look.
We're going to have a very brief moment here.
We're going to start to...
Oh.
We're going to have one shot at this.
Let me start pointing...
Opposite.
So we would like to burn somewhere there, I guess.
No.
Sorry.
Oh, wait a second.
If I'm moving faster than him...
Oh, shit.
This may not be the right...
We may have to do it opposite.
Now that I think about it.
I guess it will tell us.
Let's see where it moves if I accelerate.
Oh, wait.
Relative velocity between us is increasing.
This may not be good.
Wait.
Yeah, okay, okay, okay, okay.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
This is not good, because...
That's the...
Is the velocity coming over here?
It's coming over here.
Maybe I wait until exactly when we're crossing, and then I do it?
That's like right now.
Oh my god, I don't know.
We're going to have to get the velocity vector exactly on that.
Come on, move here.
Get over here.
Oh, but now we're moving...
Away from him?
We don't have a lot of fuel!
What's happening?
Oh, I guess we're passing.
Oh, shit, dude!
Oh, wait, is that the opposite?
That means we have to burn here.
Wait, no.
No, no, no.
Oh, fuck.
Dude, we don't have fuel for this.
A little more.
But the thing is, we have relative velocity of 100.
We're going to start drifting.
We have to burn this way.
I did the wrong way.
Relative velocity is going lower.
Dude, I don't have fuel.
Oh, shit, I fucked this up.
Wait, we only have relative velocity of 5.
Where is he?
5...
Wait, can I not?
Um...
Dude, we're going flying.
Uh...
But I guess how...
How do I control him, though?
Fuck!
Wait a minute.
Hold on.
I need to figure out how to control him.
I guess I can go to Space Center, actually.
Go to Space Center.
Space Center.
Tracking.
Carson's debris.
Yes!
Oh my god, look.
Can I see me?
Oh no.
Target.
Where are you?
EVA!
Oh my god, dude!
I'm coming!
This is awkward as hell.
Bye-bye!
Oh god.
Can I...
Oh, nice!
I do have a...
Nice, I have a vector there.
Wait.
Oh, can I...
I'm sort of going down.
It's getting less.
Oh, here we go!
19.5 meters per second.
It's increasing.
That's...
Good, I guess.
Here we go, here we go, here we go.
We just need to wait.
Can I see my fuel?
Thrust limiter.
That one.
EVA propellant!
4.71 out of 5.
We have plenty.
Right now, we're just coasting.
He's getting closer.
He's getting closer!
Oh my god.
This is sick.
Dude, this...
This...
I don't even care if we're gonna make it or not.
This is awesome!
I consider this mission a success already.
I don't give a shit.
Mmm.
Okay, maybe I need to start adjusting a little bit.
I mean, we can...
We're just approaching it right now.
We're not even using fuel.
That's fine.
Here we go.
I wonder if I can somehow...
Look, we're in orbit right now.
2,271.
Around...
Uh...
Curvan.
In a space suit.
Oh wait, we may actually start...
Uh...
Hold on, we're not moving directly towards...
Of course.
Our vector is there, and target is there.
So...
Shit.
Let me see.
Go like this.
Move it in.
Like that.
Boom.
Now our velocity vector is exactly on the target, which means we're moving directly towards it.
Oh shit, wait.
I should probably start slowing down.
Wait, this is awkward.
Why does it do like...
Why does it work?
I wish I could orient!
Can I not orient my character?
The way I want it to orient.
This is awkward, man.
Oh no, maybe I just need to go sideways.
Maybe that's the trick.
If I slow...
If I go down and slow down...
Oh no.
We gotta start slowing down, by the way.
Oh, okay.
We gotta go up.
That's the...
That's the key.
I just need to look at the velocity.
Much fuel.
Plenty.
We're actually moving away now, so that's not good.
Which means we need to...
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
You know what?
Fuck the nav ball.
I'm eyeballing it by looking at the actual target on the screen.
I don't need the nav ball for this shit.
Yes!
That's it!
Four meters per second.
We're gonna be right there.
We're gonna make it even better.
We're actually gonna be there.
The problem, though...
We don't have a lot of fuel left.
I wonder if I can...
Transfer some.
I don't think EVA propellant is...
The same as, you know, liquid fuel and, you know...
Oxidizer.
It's not the same.
But, you know...
Who knows?
4.2 meters per second.
Oh, yeah.
I wonder if you can do fuel transfers...
Somehow.
Like, let's say you have a vessel stranded...
In orbit somewhere.
And you run out of fuel.
I wonder if you can bring fuel there.
I would love to do something like that.
We're approaching!
In fact, I'm gonna speed up.
I can see the vessel!
I see it!
Isn't it beautiful?
There it is!
And I saved a spot for you, Carson.
And we're gonna pocket 40,000 credits.
Hopefully.
Okay, let's start...
Aligning a bit more here.
God, it feels good to see that...
Spaceship in the distance.
We're almost there.
Start slowing down a bit.
And there we are.
We have made it!
Ha ha ha ha!
Yo!
Let's get in!
Can I have both of these out at the same time?
Wait, how does this work now when I get in?
I'm so curious.
Oh no, wait.
RCS.
The other one.
But!
They're both inside!
Well, guys.
We have 26 Delta V.
We have a problem.
We do have jetpack fuel, though.
Wait, let me see.
Can I, like, un-target?
Whoops.
Why un-target?
Unset target.
Thank you.
83 kilometers.
I mean, if anything, we gotta burn here.
But that's not gonna be...
Shit.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Maybe when we do this, it's gonna give us a little bit of a push when we eject
that means we gotta...
Hold on.
We gotta face...
Why can't I find...
So basically, this is a rocket now, and this is the fuel.
But obviously, we're gonna burn first.
Wait, it shows me...
APWAPS is here now.
I guess that's because I got that upgrade.
That's nice.
For some reason, I thought, oh, that's because we had the target set, but no.
Okay.
Can I see the time to thingy, please?
There.
Time to APWAPS.
It's 1 minute 47.
And we have enough fuel to burn for half a second.
And right after burning, we have to disengage.
Let's fast forward a bit.
So right at APWAPS, we're gonna burn, and we're gonna discard the stage.
get ready?
7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1,
52!
That should take us in the atmosphere.
We're gonna slow down, baby.
Holy shit!
Fast forward.
But we're not done yet.
The drink shaker needs to come through the atmosphere.
This is unproven and untested.
God, I hope this works.
You gotta believe in the salt shaker.
Or whatever this is called.
I think it's just called a shaker, actually.
No, it's not even a shaker.
A shaker is the other shape.
This is the drink measurement cup thingy.
You know what?
I don't mind if we go, if we just bounce off the atmosphere here first, slow down a bit, and come back.
Or at least take a very shallow ascent here.
Or descent.
I'm totally happy with that right now.
Wait!
I misclicked.
Sorry, you guys had a little spin there.
We were on 4x speed.
I apologize.
It looked worse than it was.
Here we go.
It's starting to heat.
Barely.
But the good news is we're getting lower in orbit and our speed is getting lower.
You know what that means?
We will come back.
What?
What's...
Why is the camera doing that?
I don't like this right here.
This right here scares me.
Carson, are you gonna be alright?
Wait, is it just this part?
The aerodynamic cone there?
That's heating.
Speed up a bit.
Okay, 49 kilometers.
We are moving very fast.
And we're gonna start to heat quite a bit in a moment here.
Guys, I actually think there's a chance Carson is gonna die here.
Because of this exposed part.
I don't know how simulated that is.
But if most of the heat is...
I don't know.
Actually, I don't know.
I guess it's not it's not like this up front, right?
It's not as flat.
It's a bit of aerodynamicness going on there, right?
So, maybe it's okay.
It's gonna heat less because of that.
Not sure if that's how that works.
So far, there's no heat indicator.
We're good.
This feels good.
Wait, are their feet touching?
Or their heads are touching right now?
Uh...
Oh, they were looking at each other.
Look!
Ha-ha!
Fuck yeah!
That's amazing!
Oh...
We're not slowing down a lot here, though.
Which means we're gonna be heating for a while.
But I don't see a burn indicator or, like, a heat gauge, so I think we're okay.
Come on.
Guys, I think we may have it.
I think this one is in the bag.
I don't wanna sell the skin before the bear is shot, but I'm telling you, this is...
Uh-oh!
Looks like that upper part of the capsule is starting to heat.
You see that?
Right there.
Carson's back is getting a little hot right now.
But we're slowing down quite a bit.
I think we're okay.
Gosh, dang, man.
What is that?
Oh, the crew.
Ha ha ha!
The crew!
Yeah, we're totally...
We're chilling!
Now to...
Uh, parachute.
Parachute first.
Let's just confirm we did this in the right order.
So these are the drogues.
This is the...
Yeah.
It looks good.
The thing is, though, we have two capsules, so it's, like, it's gonna be more weight, you know?
So I don't know the speed at which we're gonna impact the Earth with.
That's the thing I'm a little troubled by right now.
Okay.
Let's deploy chutes.
Now.
Drogues are up.
And we're going straight into a thunderstorm.
Lovely.
Main chutes.
Up.
The shaker.
It's coming back.
Oh-ho!
Why does that look like a room for crazy people in there?
There's something off with the shading on that.
It looks weird.
Like a padded room.
Let's just enjoy this, shall we?
Man.
What a trip.
There goes the chutes.
Are we gonna splash down or touchdown?
Oh, man.
Imagine the chutes just get destroyed.
I think we're over water.
I'm not entirely sure.
Nice.
Main chutes are up.
Oi!
We just spun around like that.
Uh-oh.
We're gonna impact like that?
I don't know if that's good.
This may be a problem.
Nah, look.
Five meters per second?
That's very slow.
Hopefully it's okay.
But, uh, I do feel for Carson a little bit here.
But you know what?
That's his punishment for getting stuck in orbit anyway.
Doofus.
I mean, fast forward a bit.
Oh!
Cacti!
So we're in the desert.
Sweet.
There's one there.
Man.
Shitty weather, huh?
Actually, yeah.
The further down we go, the slower we should move because there's dense air.
So now we're at 4.8-ish.
Oh, God.
We're gonna impact with the pointy end.
Hey!
Not bad!
Very nice!
Recover that bastard!
Ha ha!
That was beautiful!
We did it.
Wonderful.
We got some...
We got 40,000 in the bank.
Hey!
Oh!
We get to keep him!
Oh, I didn't realize that was...
Oh, that's amazing!
That means we don't have to hire more.
And he got experience from it, too.
That's sweet.
Uh, let me see that again.
No.
Here?
This one.
What is he?
He's a pilot!
Yes!
This is the new Jebediah.
Carson is the new guy.
He is him.
Wonderful.
Valentina has three orbits around the moon.
What?
Does she?
Maybe I'm remembering wrong.
I feel like she doesn't have that.
But, uh...
Okay.
Sure.
Whatever.
Um...
What's next?
Okay, well, that was kind of challenging.
Obviously, next time we're gonna bring more fuel for that.
I also realized something else.
Maybe we should have a better setup for storing the Kerbal.
Like, the shaker worked, but I didn't like it.
Not a fan.
I think we're gonna, you know, wait with that until we get something better.
Next up is gonna be Moon again.
Because I want science, baby.
Science!
Not for Clampatron, though!
Okay, I like these guys.
Stedtler.
Ooh, that's a lot of money.
Measure temperature in...
Oh, wait, what?
Are these sites or areas on the moon?
Bro, that sounds incredibly difficult.
Rescue...
Oh, I thought it said harvester.
Explore carbon?
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
We need to test our rendezvous capabilities.
Park two vessels next to each other around Kerban.
Brother.
Have you not been keeping track?
Oh, but...
But I guess I didn't.
I guess I didn't technically have two vessels next to each other.
Right.
That's true.
I was...
I took the distance on foot, so to speak.
So that makes sense.
Um...
But this sounds like...
It says trivial.
I feel like it's not that trivial, but okay.
We can take that.
This one seems insanely difficult.
Because first off, you gotta go to the moon.
And...
Oh, look at this.
Below...
Below nine kilometers?
That's like right above the surface, isn't it?
Like nothing.
Test heat shield splashdown.
I mean, that's an easy one.
But maybe we gotta do these, uh...
Shitty missions, you know?
To make room for new ones.
Let me see the archives.
Oh, look at all this.
This one I canceled because this was Clampatron, and we hate those guys.
Don't like them.
Um...
Maybe we could do something like this.
Take pressure readings.
But that's like...
Weird.
Science data from space around Kerbin.
That sounds doable.
Let's take that one.
Easy.
And then, uh, we can take...
I guess we can take this one.
Yeah, maybe we'll have two vessels next to each other up there.
Maybe we can experiment with fuel transfer, then.
Because that's something I want to figure out.
Maybe this says something.
Cargo...
Wait, cargo storage unit.
Oh, okay.
EVA...
I want the EVA thingy with the experiment.
Where did I see that?
Is it that one?
EVA experiments kit.
90...
Oh, wait.
We don't have enough science.
Oh.
Uh-oh.
Well, that's not good.
What's that?
Rovemax?
Oh, rovers?
Dude, I can't even imagine rovers.
Right now.
Survivability.
Wait, we actually have a landing strut.
Dude, should we try and land on the moon?
I feel like I have what I need.
I have money.
I can do many missions before I'm broke.
Many, many missions.
Open my...
Jebediah.
Because this is the one.
And then...
Let me think.
How would I do this?
A small landing leg.
Designed for space probes or lightweight landers.
Basically made of toothpicks.
Space-grade toothpicks, mind you.
But be careful with them anyway.
Tolerance 10 meters per second.
I guess you want...
Something like that.
Huh.
Wait, deploy shielded?
What does that mean?
Ah!
Cool!
Fits the booster thingy.
Oh, wait.
If we were to do this...
See, that's no good.
That's bad.
These legs are not long enough.
We're gonna have to move them down.
Oh, but that doesn't look stable at all.
That could work.
Is this a...
Wait, is this a terrible idea?
I feel like it's also way too tall.
Wait a sec.
Wait, let's actually do the contract instead.
I feel like this is too much for me.
I can't even think about this right now.
But you would just go into orbit and then obviously go suborbital and start burning as you reach the ground.
And it's not that hard.
This one...
I think I get rid of...
No, I actually keep it.
I keep it.
Because we want to go around Kerbin now.
Actually, we're gonna take two vessels up there.
Yeah.
What else?
Didn't I also unlock a bunch of new shit, by the way?
All this.
Look at this.
Drain...
Drain valve!
What's that?
While trying to solve the initial issue with the FTX-1 series fuel line, an engineer at Floyd Dynamics had an ingenious thought.
What if you failed to attach a fuel pipe at all?
Solves the issue of making sure the fuel goes in the right direction.
Because it just goes out.
He was demoted and assigned to bookkeeping duties.
But later on, Floyd resurrected his idea in the form of the FTE-1.
A valve that will allow you to drain most resources from the part that it happens to be attached to.
Great for emergencies.
Flotation adjustment.
Or...
Just fun rocket pranks.
When is this good?
I'm trying to think.
When would this ever be a good idea?
Maybe if you connect this external fuel duct.
I was about to say if you connect it to a pipe.
New breakthroughs of Floyd Dynamics have made the FTX fuel duct a reality.
Although criticized by some as being no more than a sewage pipe painted yellow, most agree that the yellow is a relatively nice color.
And that fuel lines are indeed able to pump fuel from one...
Or from side-mounted fuel tanks.
After the recall of the FTX-1 series, all FTX-2 lines have arrows painted on to indicate the fuel flow direction.
So engineers can tell which way they are supposed to go.
Okay, so I guess you want to...
Put the drain valve.
And then put the...
One end of this on that.
And then you want to put this on an input valve?
That I don't have, I guess?
I'm actually not entirely sure...
How that would work.
Let me buy this.
Buy this.
Oh, that's cool.
But how...
Hmm.
Because I'm thinking...
The way I envision this is that...
We rendezvous in orbit...
And then you transfer fuel from one...
Oh my god, bro.
Dude, imagine boosting up like a massive tank of fuel...
Then going up with a...
Sorry, I just got something in my throat.
And then you go up with another rocket...
And then you just refuel.
And you're good to go.
Whoa, dude.
We gotta do that.
But we gotta figure out how to do this first.
So this is obviously...
You can connect this tank to this tank.
But aren't they already connected?
Maybe you need this first.
Oh, they're so small?
What the...
Okay, maybe they don't actually belong on it.
So what is the point of that?
When would you like to just drain fuel?
Hmm.
I feel like we're missing a part.
Hold on.
I predict it's gonna be like an intake valve or something.
A few...
Fuel systems...
Advanced fuel systems?
No?
Maybe there's something in another category?
Um...
I don't know.
No, it's gotta be like...
Maybe you're able to move these around in EVA.
Maybe that's what it is.
That's the only thing I can think of.
Like, you put this here...
And then maybe when you're in EVA, you can...
Take the, uh...
The output side...
And move it to somewhere else.
You know what I mean?
You know what?
Why am I asking?
I can just try it.
Right now.
We make a super simplified version of something.
Let me open, um...
A simple one.
Science 1.
This one.
We don't even need...
Uh, we do need this.
We don't need this.
Let's say we have a little tank.
There, right?
Get rid of this.
Don't need that, because we're not launching.
And...
The flag is horrible.
Actually, the flag is nice, but...
You know, there's issues with the flag.
And now?
Uh, let me do...
Another one.
Let me...
Let me empty this.
So we empty?
Oh, what?
Why you do that?
Huh?
Oh, maybe it doesn't want to, because...
It's technically one fuel tank now?
So perhaps we need something in between.
Like, let's say we do this.
And then we put a fuel tank.
Empty it.
Boom.
Whoops.
This guy there.
Aha!
Now it works.
Okay, let's see.
Ah!
But we have an issue!
I can't quite...
Reach.
Unless I can.
What's...
What's this flashing here?
What's going on there?
Well, I don't know why I...
Okay, so I can't do that.
Get in.
Uh, let me actually consult the manual.
Let's see if there's anything about fuel.
Management screens.
Maneuver.
Rocketry?
Advanced.
Basics.
Cargos.
Recharging supplies.
Fuel cells.
Maybe.
No, this is not it.
Hmm.
Maybe this will become clear later.
That's okay.
I don't need to...
Become an expert on that right now.
I was just curious.
Whatever.
Okay.
Give me my other one that I had.
Was it that one?
I think so.
Yeah.
And I do want to bring the Science Junior with me.
Let's actually make this even more powerful.
Wait, 24 tons.
Seven.
Oh.
So it's like way more.
Let's try something here.
Check it out.
Let's try these, shall we?
X.
And then...
Let's do two of these.
It's on two.
Is that just...
Oh, it does go on like that.
Whee!
That looks amazing.
Whoa.
Now that's a rocket right there.
That's beautiful.
Beautiful.
And...
Aerodynamics.
Let's do this.
Oh, yeah.
Actually, I want to move these further down so it's not balancing on that.
That's kind of crazy.
I need to be aligned.
And then...
Actually, maybe a little further down is good.
Whoops.
There we go.
Beautiful.
That's it.
Oh, this is going to look amazing.
Oh, wait a minute.
I guess I want to eject somewhere in the upper part of this.
So that they don't fly...
Like this, you know?
And bounce into the rocket.
We would want to...
Eject them outwards so that they...
You know what I mean?
So even further down, really.
So let's just move...
And a bit more.
There we go.
Nah, one more.
I guess we want to turn all these on at the same time.
And then when these run out, we go like...
Oof, bye-bye.
And then when this engine runs out...
We activate this.
I guess we don't need to do it simultaneously.
Because we're going to be quite high up.
And we may not want to burn immediately.
So the reason I'm going for these two instead of the...
The big one is that two of these is like two-thirds or so of one of these.
In terms of fuel.
Or technically mass, right?
But this one is a little too crazy just for going to orbit.
So that's why I don't want to use it.
It's also cheaper.
Let's call this...
Actually, there's no name for this.
This is a...
Vessel.
Just a vessel.
This will be a placeholder for a lot of things.
Who's in it?
Let's give Carson...
Oh, actually, no.
I'm going to keep Valentina because I kind of want to level her up.
I need to see what happens when you get higher levels.
Okay.
Go.
Time to launch.
Ooh, I have a great idea.
We're...
We're going to rendezvous, of course.
But the other one that comes up is a scientist.
So that we can reset things.
Amazing.
All right.
Let's give it a whirl, shall we?
Hey!
Actually, we're going quite fast.
I'm actually going to...
Slow down the liquid fuel here.
Wait, are they bending?
That looks unstable as hell.
Look at that.
They're sort of bending inward slightly.
That ain't good.
I'll start turning a little bit here.
Oh, it's starting to rotate for some reason.
Okay, maybe that's not a good idea.
Oh, God.
Oh!
Okay, I love this.
Those decouplers are amazing.
But we didn't manage to turn at all because of that.
So this was a bad rocket, actually.
This is a bad rocket.
Bad rocket.
Oh, I need more speed.
What am I doing?
I'm trying to compensate for the lag of turn earlier.
Wait, what the...
What's that orbit?
Oh!
We have space junk now.
Oh, shit.
That ain't good.
Dude, we have to, like, keep the space clean.
We need a way to de-orbit these, uh...
defunct...
parts here.
Nice.
And now I can see the...
I can also click here.
150.
That's way too much.
Yeah, this rocket was not ideal.
Whee!
I'm gonna start burning now.
Right there.
We're not aligned.
Actually, we were aligned.
We want to align right there.
Yeah, burned a little too late.
But maybe that's okay.
We have a bit of a bigger or higher orbit here.
And then the next vessel that comes up is gonna have a bit of a smaller orbit.
So we can catch up, I guess.
But the easy...
This is gonna be kinda easy.
Because we have two vessels we can control now.
You know?
Oh, I don't like the way this orbit is developing.
Yeah, this is ugly.
I burned way too late.
Shit.
Good enough.
Actually, maybe I do like that it's kinda...
eccentric.
Just slightly.
Yo.
Actually.
Hold on.
So I don't know what the actual...
Like, if you were to work at NASA, right?
And you were to rendezvous two vehicles...
You'd probably calculate this shit.
Ideally, right?
But...
I don't know what the...
High-level concept, like...
Idea is here.
Like, what the optimal way to do it is.
But I'm thinking right now, since we have an eccentric orbit here...
And we just get another vessel up...
That has a perfectly circular orbit...
With its periapsis being right at the same elevation as the periapsis of the eccentric orbit...
Then I guess, over time, they're gonna meet at some point.
It may take a long time.
But it's gonna happen at some point.
So it's all about how many snacks you brought.
Really.
Valentina's excited.
Because we're in orbit.
Hell yeah.
Okay.
That's one vessel.
So I guess we just...
Space center.
Oh no.
The weather is shit.
No such thing as bad weather for a launch.
Okay.
For the next rocket...
I guess we're gonna...
We don't need any signs on that one.
Let's say that.
Don't care.
Get rid of it.
There we go.
Right.
Yeah.
Nice.
And you know what?
We don't need...
This is too much.
It's doing too much.
We just need one.
So...
It was a little over-engineered.
This is beautiful.
In fact, I wanna make these even prettier.
Let's give it...
Oh, wait a minute.
Give me that one.
Ha ha!
Even better.
Sweet.
Get rid of these.
That's too much.
And then...
That one.
Make him white.
Yeah.
Someone's texting me.
Whatever.
Okay.
Simple rocket.
Nothing to overthink here.
This goes.
That goes.
Boom, boom, boom.
Easy.
Okay.
And that's a launch.
Wait, who's going?
It's gotta be Bob.
I should've put Bob in the other vessel.
That would've been ideal.
But I guess we're...
Attempting to rendezvous, so it doesn't matter.
Time for Bob.
Bob, you glorious bastard.
You're going up.
Wait a second, though.
Yay!
You're going up.
The weather is bad.
But that's okay.
And we're off.
Oh yeah, we can't do this.
Oh.
Okay.
I gotta pay attention here.
This could go wrong.
So far, we're pretty straight.
Should've maybe added some fins at the end.
Poor man's SAS.
Slightly turn right.
Oh.
We're moving a little wrong there.
Time to...
Next stage.
Oh my god.
The timing on that with the thunder.
It's kind of cool.
Oh my god.
It's so weird without SAS.
I'm so used to the SAS now.
We're turning way too much, dude.
Calm down, calm down, calm down, calm down.
Oh no.
Turbulent weather.
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
Keep the velocity on the line.
Let's just...
Exactly prograde right now.
Uh, 18,000.
Go a little more horizontal, maybe.
Like here.
We're gonna run out of fuel here.
Sayonara!
So long.
Oh, shit.
I thought we would go way higher with that.
Let me actually look at this instead.
Dude, this button down here has been amazing.
I feel like I should have used that earlier.
This is spending a lot of fuel.
I gotta get above 70 at least.
Okay, there we go.
We go a little further though.
Oh, I got it perfect there.
Not bad.
In fact, go higher.
Let's try and at least match the height of that orbit there.
Unless this is...
Oh, that's Carson's debris!
Shit!
Wait, where's the lowest part of...
Actually, it's decent.
There we go.
And then we're gonna burn approximately up here.
So how long does it usually take for us to do this?
It's like, what, 30 seconds or so of burning?
So maybe I wait until we are...
15 seconds from...
Apoapsis.
But I'm also a little higher and a little more horizontal than usual.
So let's just say like 12.
Let's say 12.
There we go.
Why is it so hard to keep straight?
Keep it straight!
Oh!
I forget about the precision keybind.
Oh, it's much easier now.
Oh my god.
I feel like I used that in the first stream when I played this.
And then I forgot about it since.
Fucking beautiful.
Wonderful.
Okay, now.
That's Carson's debris.
See, I shouldn't have named them the same thing.
But that's okay.
Oh, Switch 2!
Oh!
That's much easier!
Oh my god.
That's gonna make it so much easier.
I was like, am I gonna have to go back and forth between...
Space Tracker, or whatever it's called.
You know, the tracking center.
Set us target.
So let me think about this.
Okay, here's the plan.
We're gonna go to Apoapsis.
And then we're gonna burn until we at least match the elevation here.
And then we're gonna see what happens.
This is gonna be a little bit of experimentation.
Because I honestly have no idea what's going on.
We got a little lucky last time that we just happened to launch straight into...
Carson, you know?
But this time, it's a little different.
We're almost at Apoapsis.
Dude, it's helped so much to see that on the map there.
Now we burn...
Prograde.
Oh, wait a minute!
We're actually kind of close?
Hey!
Ah, 17 kilometers.
Not that close, actually.
Never mind.
The line, it's...
Okay.
So, wait.
The thing I'm not understanding...
It says...
It says intersect one.
Let me just see what happens if I go around a bit.
I mean, we could just...
We could start burning towards it.
If you think about it.
What does it say?
29 kilometers?
It's like...
It's not that far.
Is it?
Wait, 29 kilometers.
That is kind of far.
Never mind.
I kind of want to...
If I burn a little faster now...
Wait, where am I going to be?
So, I'm going to be a little behind.
Okay.
Ah, but this is not actually going to...
If I do this...
Let me see.
Yeah, yeah.
As I suspected.
Yeah, it's going to...
It's making it worse.
So, then let's try and slow down a bit.
Because if we slow...
It sounds...
Okay, this is the thing.
It sounds very...
Counterintuitive.
But if we slow down now, we're actually going to catch up to him.
Right?
Because we're in a gravitational field.
And if we're in a lower orbit, we move faster.
You know what I mean?
But it doesn't look like we're going to...
I mean, we're burning very slowly, though.
As soon as we hit, like, a minimum or something, we're going to stop.
If it starts to go the opposite way, you know?
Okay, this looks about right.
Maybe.
I have plenty of fuel.
I'll say that.
One thing I wish to know, though.
So, we're...
We currently have a relative velocity...
Jeez, I can't speak.
We have a relative velocity between us of 36 meters per second.
And that's going to be closing.
So, I'm moving towards it right now.
And I'm going to...
Overtake him at some point.
Because my lower...
My orbit is lower.
So, that means I'm going to be moving away from him soon.
So, I guess I just start burning towards him.
Right?
So, the target...
Is there.
And we are currently pointing that way with our velocity.
Oh,
wait.
Maybe I should do this on the other vessel, actually.
Because...
Hold on.
Switch two.
Because that one has SAS.
Hello?
And now, map.
Target.
Okay.
I don't have a lot of fuel on this one, though.
Ew.
That's the problem.
That's the issue.
I need to understand this, though.
So, right now, he's going to overtake us.
So, we're...
Getting closer.
If I...
Where's my velocity vector?
Fuck.
Where is it?
There.
Okay.
And the target?
Where's the target?
There.
Okay, okay, okay.
So, here.
Bring it down here.
Now, we don't want to go too fast, either.
This is a problem.
Boom!
Okay, now we need to start slowing down.
Because we're going to be coming in hot.
Point opposite.
Because we want to bring that on top of it.
Oh, wait.
Oh, right.
We're pointing the other way, so...
Oh, that's...
We have to do this.
30 meters per second.
I feel like it's not good.
I'm moving away from him right now.
No, I'm not.
I'm not.
I'm moving towards him.
Actually, maybe it's okay if we go a little faster, because...
There's a long way between us.
Burn a little harder, maybe.
Wait, 70 meters per second.
Let's just...
Speed up a little bit here.
This is a funny dance.
Okay, so he's obviously overtaking.
Which means, ideally, I want to be pointing towards here and start matching his speed.
Me just going towards him is actually wrong.
That's really what I want to do.
Yeah, I guess that makes sense.
That's what I've been doing.
He's only six kilometers away.
We actually have got a...
Oh, God.
Fuck.
We need to...
Slow down.
Wait.
So, wait.
Our retro is pointing...
Fuck.
No.
Here, here, here.
There.
I guess.
Okay.
Wait.
What did I say here?
Within visual range.
Okay.
That's very...
I mean, we are technically...
I can see it from here.
I see the vessel.
Oh, look at that.
Oh, wait.
We have a 0.3 kilometer intersect.
So, this is...
This is just going to activate automatically.
All we do is wait.
Fuck yeah.
No problem.
Also, I did not pay attention to my fuel at all, but we still have some.
That's fine.
But we have to remember, as soon as we get there, we got to start slowing down.
Otherwise, we're just going to pass by each other.
But maybe that's okay.
I mean, we're not...
What am I even trying to do?
Nah, you know what?
We should try and slow down so that we're right next to each other and, you know, we fly in formation.
That is cool.
Oh, the problem is we're moving into darkness where I can't see shit.
Uh-oh.
Can I see...
Uh...
Targets...
One minute, 30 seconds.
Okay.
Speed up a bit.
Let me just do this.
There we go.
And maybe we approach it a little slower.
Wait.
What if my engines...
I don't...
So, this is the question.
Are they simulating if my engines blast on that?
So...
Like, if I point straight at it, that's...
Hmm.
Let's see.
It's probably not.
It's probably fine.
Maybe it...
Okay, maybe I actually...
There it is.
We got it.
No problem.
Wait, why can't I turn the thing anymore?
I can't turn the thing.
Hold on.
Emergency!
I gotta use the other one.
Wait.
No, no, no, no, no.
Fuck!
I can't click on it!
No, that's Carson.
You idiot.
It's right there.
Oh, God.
Oh, they almost hit each other!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus
fucking Christ.
I guess we want to break like this.
Okay, yeah.
They're not simulating the outflow hitting it.
There it is!
If it had simulated the actual exhaust hitting the rocket, I would be cooked here.
0.0.
I would say that's pretty good.
We're close.
Wait, I need to experiment with something here.
Wait.
So, can I just right-click immediately and go like...
Switch 2 or something?
There's no...
Like, hold on.
There's gotta be a way.
Because I can't...
I literally can't click on the map because they're right on top of each other.
Like, I can't.
Not working.
Maybe there's, like, a way to do it.
What about keybinds?
What do we have?
Oh, God.
I closed it.
Flight.
Wait.
Lock current stage?
You can lock it?
Interesting.
A little landing gear.
EVA.
Jet rotate?
Oh, Q&E.
Okay.
Wait.
Adjust jet heading via mouse.
Drag left mouse button?
What?
I gotta try that.
Jetpack.
Cycle through active ships.
Oh, but wait.
Oh, no.
This is like an American fucking keyboard thing.
I don't have that key.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Is it this one?
Oh, my God.
Much better.
Beautiful.
If in doubt, consult the cheat sheet.
Okay.
So, what was I doing again?
Oh, right.
We want to do...
Science!
Yes.
Also, what orbit are we in right now?
Right.
I guess I matched the eccentric orbit, so we're in that one.
Cool.
Man, it's so dark.
We need to wait until daylight, I feel like.
We are drifting apart slightly, or moving towards each other.
It's hard to say.
Ah, we're moving...
We're actually kind of...
It's a little funky, the way this is.
The orbits are not precise.
Bye-bye.
There we go.
Light.
Okay, nice.
So.
Science.
That's what we needed to do.
0.1 science.
Come on.
I guess I already did everything here.
Is it even worth it to reset anything?
Maybe the whole Bob idea was useless.
Hey, 3.3.
That's something.
Okay.
Well, we can maybe do a EVA.
EVA report.
Hey, 4.8.
That's something.
Oh my gosh.
I'm in space.
Hell yeah, you are.
I mean, Valentina, you've been in space before.
You've been to the moon.
But I get your enthusiasm.
Close doors.
No, actually, I need to go grab that.
So, like this.
Like this.
And now...
So wait, I need to see this drag left mouse button.
Oh, shit.
Look.
I can angle my...
Oh, shit.
Dude, I need to look at this cheat sheet some more.
But it's kind of weird the way that...
Oh, yeah.
I guess I can rotate with Q and E as well.
Oh, interesting.
Okay, well.
That's nice.
Whoops.
Down.
Collect data.
And we want to put it in there.
And then we want to enter again.
Close up.
Okay.
Let's get back, shall we?
Actually, I want to try something.
Wait, what?
Ah.
I guess the Kerbal in itself counts as a vessel.
We got to go say hi in space, don't we?
I'm coming!
Valentina!
It's me!
It's Bob!
The science man!
Bob Kerman, the science guy.
Uh-oh, we're coming in fast.
Hey!
Yo, this is so cool!
What's going on, friend?
Rendezvous!
What do you say we do some rendezvous up in that pod up there, huh?
Just kidding.
Don't want HR coming down on us.
Can I, can we, like, do anything, like, transfer propellant or something?
Can I take her jetpack?
Oh my god!
Wait, what is the...
Oh, that's the parachute, I guess.
Okay, so if you can do this, there's gotta be, like, a way to...
Maybe you need, like, a little device, so we can transfer fuel, for example.
In case we ever need to, right?
Anyway.
High five.
Oh, sorry.
Sorry.
Bye-bye.
Nice seeing ya.
Alright.
Bye-bye.
Oh, that's so funny.
This game is so much fun, man.
Who would've thunk?
A space lover loves space game.
It's almost unbelievable.
Oh
man, the planet is so bright.
Let's not fall into this thing here.
I'm getting quite proficient at the jetpack.
Where's, wait, where's the entrance?
Aha!
There it is.
Done.
Oi!
Sorry.
I'm sorry about that.
Let's get you back inside.
Oh man.
I wish I could somehow more easily angle my...
So I can do this, of course.
But it feels, like, not good.
There's gotta be, like, another way to...
If I...
Let's say I wanna just reorient my camera like this, and then have her point in that direction.
Like, not from her feet, but you know what I mean?
Like, instead of having to do this...
And look, she even auto-adjusts back to...
Hmm.
Wait, let me check the cheat sheet again.
Maybe there's something about that.
Uh, I guess that would...
EVA.
Reorient heading to camera by jet.
What does that even mean?
Oh.
Okay, well that's just...
What?
Wait.
Toggle headlamps?
That's not working.
Is that one?
Oh my god!
We have a light!
Holy shit!
That's amazing!
Okay, what else can I do?
Toggle movement mode?
The mod key is dependent on your operating system.
Windows, alt.
Okay.
It's not doing anything.
Liar.
Maybe, maybe...
Okay, maybe this cheat sheet isn't, uh...
Reflecting the in-game keybinds right now.
Maybe the default keybinds in the game have changed over the years.
Uh, so I don't know.
Let's just get back inside.
This is good.
Successful mission is successful.
Alright, let's start burning, shall we?
We're going home.
Uh.
SAS.
Wait, why...
Why can't I...
Am I in a weird...
mode here or something?
Dude, I can't...
Are we missing something?
Electric charge?
Oxidizer's also...
Oh, that's kind of cool.
The way it sort of...
Shows the overlay.
Wait a minute.
Oh, maybe it is actually.
Maybe you need the electric charge...
To reaction wheel.
So wait, am I fucked?
Ah, wait.
We can turn on the engine, I guess.
That's one way.
We can gimbal that.
Or, I mean, we're rotating right now.
If you just wait...
Wait, I have an idea.
This is so dumb.
Watch this.
So wait, I want it to...
I want the engine to point that way.
So we're just going to do a little pit maneuver.
Valentina, I hope this helmet has good, sturdy construction.
It actually works.
Get in, get in, get in, get in, get in.
Oh, God.
Quick, quick, quick, quick, quick.
No, no, no, no, no.
Get up, get up, up, up, up.
Crap.
Get in.
Ah, we missed it.
But it's going to keep rotating.
I love the whimsical nature...
Of this whole mission.
It's so dumb.
Wait, no.
Fuck.
I did it wrong.
Well, bye-bye.
We are gone now.
See ya.
Part of me wants to try and place a...
Okay, here we go.
Wait, what's happening?
What?
I don't know what I'm doing!
Wait!
It's because I have a target, dude!
I'm being confused!
Onset target!
Where are you?
Fuck!
I know what's happening!
I understand!
That's got...
That's got to be like a keybind for that.
But I can't bother with that right now.
Yeah, now...
Look, orbit!
God damn, dude!
Okay, fuck it.
Just...
Fuel!
Shit!
Hey, good news!
We're at AP right now!
Come on, turn, turn, turn, turn, turn, turn, turn!
Yeah!
Retro!
And...
Booyah!
That was it!
Disengage!
Shit!
Yeah!
Okay, so we may have a problem here.
Bro, this fucking number down here.
Oh!
You can actually switch reference frame.
This number here confused the fuck out of me.
It also put the wrong things on here because it was using the target as the reference.
So I was just blindly burning or trusting the instruments when I should have just trusted my gut here.
Shit balls!
Uh...
Oh!
Okay, so I can't actually do that when I'm not close.
Okay.
Uh...
Well, we have a problem then because we can't really get home.
Unless I move up with the other rocket and push it.
But it's rotating, so...
Good luck with that.
We may have to come up here and get Valentina out of...
You know what?
Okay, who do I value more?
Valentina or Bob?
Sometimes you have to make these decisions, you know?
Hmm.
Like, I think I value Valentina more, but we're 16 kilometers away.
We're fucked, dude.
Oh, I can't believe I've done this.
I thought I had more fuel.
We're cooked.
Unless...
Can I...
I have an idea.
This is so dumb.
Split these chutes.
Oh.
Oh, I can actually...
We're gonna point one way and deploy chutes along our retro.
If you think about it, it's like throwing...
Now, I guess it's attached.
So there's no nets, you know, exhaust here.
Fuck.
Hmm.
Well, shit.
You know what?
This is...
This is why I wanted to figure out how to transfer fuel.
For exactly this reason.
I mean, now it's too late anyway, because we disengaged here.
But, you know.
It is what it is.
We're gonna have to come back and rescue Valentina.
That's where we're at right now.
It's unfortunate.
She's gonna be up here a while.
God damn it, man.
I can't believe that.
Okay.
Let's not...
Can I just...
See?
There you go.
Much easier.
Wait.
Surface.
I guess I wanna...
Wait a second.
I'm trying to understand why these numbers are different.
This is just directly according to surface.
My speed.
Like, if you were to measure my...
Speed across the surface.
Okay.
Right.
Okay, well, we are gonna point towards...
Retrograde.
And we have so much fuel, like, it doesn't even matter.
Somehow, Bob, the non-pilot...
Came up here with better fuel management.
Then again.
I think it was Valentina who spent a lot of fuel to get to Bob.
So maybe it's not quite a fair thing to say.
Ah, Bob did alright overall.
I don't care where I burn.
I'm just gonna burn.
Wonderful.
That's all a man needs.
Oh, wait a sec.
All the science is on that one.
I guess when we...
Wait.
Hold on.
How do you...
I guess we would...
If we bring up a crew...
KRU...
Then we're gonna bring Valentina back and we're gonna grab the science on the way back as well.
Oh my god.
Ah, I can't believe it.
What a shitshow of a mission.
But hey.
We're having fun, right?
Okay.
Let's head back.
Can't warp faster than 50x while below 120.
Okay.
Let's start pointing.
Whoa, that's very sensitive.
Oh, this is the problem now.
We don't have SAS.
So I actually have to be on my toes here.
During re-entry.
There's no hand-holding.
Oh!
Jesus Christ.
I don't like the spinning.
Stop the spinning.
I wonder how much easier this would be if I actually had a joystick.
Connected.
Look, it's automatically sort of stabilizing around retro now.
That's actually good.
I like that.
A little faster.
As soon as it starts heating, we're gonna have to start paying attention.
Oh!
Why does the camera do that?
Here we go.
Actually, it's better if I don't touch the controls.
Jesus.
The wheel.
You must take it.
Right, I can speed up a little bit.
Dude, I love this part.
Oh, man.
Valentina is stuck in orbit.
Hmm.
Imagine we go up to try to rescue her and we get stranded with those as well because we fuck it up.
We're just gonna have more and more people up there.
They should be fine.
I like the planets and the moon there.
The planets and the moons are there.
Beautiful.
Staying right on retro.
Last time when I was with Bob, it was very unstable because we did not just have a capsule with a heat shield.
We had, like, a science department in front that then exploded.
So that was made it...
That's what made it super unstable and I had to really fine adjust all the way down, you know?
And my hand actually hurt from that.
Because I was continuously tapping and I was using a lot of muscles in my fingers without thinking because I was so nervous, you know?
I forgot how much money we're getting for this contract.
But it should be a sizable amount.
And maybe we can upgrade some more facilities.
Okay.
The capsule is wanting to turn over a little bit now.
I'm a little nervous about that.
I'm gonna try and keep it...
Oh, wait.
We have parachutes.
Nice.
Okay.
We're totally chilling.
This is fine.
And then we can deploy this one.
Same procedure as every year.
God, this UI is just a flashbang.
And it's apparently...
It's still the...
It's the dark mode UI and still.
The game is just dark, you know?
Dude, look at that.
I wonder if I can rotate this.
Oh, yeah.
KSP.
That's the moon.
I was there earlier.
Good times.
Dude, you can zoom a lot here.
Like, does he have, like, binoculars or something?
You can...
You can see the craters.
From this zoom.
Holy shit.
Maybe they have built-in zoomers in their eyes.
These weird kerbals.
Okay.
Splashing down.
Ah, Valentina's gonna have to wait.
Limited crew control.
Why is that?
Oh, not connected?
I guess we can't see any of the connection sites.
No signal.
Bob made it home.
One of two.
So far, so good.
No experience for that?
I feel like he deserves experience.
After that performance.
Also, next up, we're gonna have to try and focus on some science.
Because I want to get more...
Oh my god.
Look at how much there is in this...
How the hell am I gonna get enough science for all of this?
I'm already, like, questioning how on earth this is gonna happen.
Maybe when you land on the moon and, you know, plant the flag and do EVA report and stuff, it's gonna be valuable like crazy.
That's my guess.
I mean, otherwise...
These things, you know, are like 160.
300, right?
This one is a thousand!
It's gotta go up exponentially.
Okay, well, let's stop it there.
Save the game.
Very, very, uh...
productive session, I would say.
Four hours.
Okay, not bad.
I was planning on four-ish hours.
I mean, this game...
You cannot play this game unless you're in complete darkness.
Otherwise, how are you gonna even see anything when you're on the dark side of the planet and stuff?
Oh, man.
Guys!
We actually went to the moon.
And we didn't land, but...
The main goal was completed.
Next time, we're gonna land on the moon.
We got to honor Jeb.
You're right.
Jebediah.
Was Jebediah the rocket that actually...
got us in orbit around the moon?
I'm getting the names mixed up now.
Yeah, this was...
This was a nice session.
W Space Program.
W Pilot.
Thank you.
I mean, Valentina is really the one who did it.
How good were those eclipses?
Right?
Am I crazy?
Or does that not happen as often as it did right now?
I felt lucky with that.
We had, like, three in the span of, what, 30 minutes or something?
Or an hour.
Next time, we steal the moon.
You know...
You know what would be fitting?
If the moon was actually made of cheese in this game.
It would fit the whimsical nature of it.
Imagine you could go there and then right-click the surface and be like, take a bite.
Or...
sample the moon, you know?
You eat a little bit of it.
A cheese experiment.
Don't forget, you don't have to use the stock KSP flags.
You can change the game files for custom mission flags.
Really?
But, I mean, I'm happy with the flag, I guess.
You made me one?
I don't want to sound ungrateful, but what if I don't like it?
I don't want to be like, nah, I don't want to put it up because I...
So I'm just going to say, I'm just going to use the current flag.
I don't want to not end up liking it, you know what I mean?
How dark is your room?
It's not that dark now because I turned on the lights.
But it was pretty dark throughout all this.
How do you feel about the difficulty?
I think it's fitting.
I'm having a blast with it.
I'm glad I picked hard.
I think it's so much more fun when the stakes are high.
But I always do that in games, so it's...
it's not a big surprise.
For me, at least.
When is next Hungry Pigaxe?
I'm going to say the...
tomorrow?
Or the day after tomorrow?
One of them, 100%.
You seem very in your soul...
Dude, I am loved...
This is exactly up my alley.
I, like, I know shit about...
I know stuff about this, you know?
I get to actually apply some of the...
some of the logic, I guess, that I have in me.
It's amazing.
That spacewalk was a 10 out of 10 cinema quality?
Nice.
I think so, too.
It was great.
I'm also loving the progression, actually.
So I knew there was going to be a campaign.
That's one of the reasons I really wanted to play this now.
But I didn't expect it to be that good.
Like, the progression is nailed here.
The only thing I'll say is maybe...
maybe the...
Nah, no, actually I'm not going to say anything because it feels like I'm still missing a lot.
You know?
And I will learn in time.
Some of the contracts seem very difficult.
You know?
Well, Yugi-Stan, I'm not technically a new player.
I did play this before, remember?
And I actually did land on the moon.
But that was with, like...
when the game first came out and it was, like, a fully new game and I guess I used good parts or whatever.
But yeah, so I do have some intuition behind it, you know, from that.
But still.
I really enjoy just...
exploring this solar system.
and figuring out things as I go along.
But still, the intuition is still there and it's crazy.
I guess.
I think what's helping me a lot here is thinking in terms of vectors, you know?
Like, the way I imagine it, there's always, like, an arrow pointing out of my ship in a certain direction.
Which is represented by, you know, the...
the prograde symbol on...
on the nav ball.
But, like, even in 3D space, I'm, like, imagining this arrow pointing.
So, for example, when I tried to, uh, get close to the other vessel, that arrow was pointing off-center from that vessel, right?
It was like, oh, I just point...
I just apply forces in opposite directions from that arrow to make the arrow align with the direction of the vessel.
So, like, in that way, I guess it...
I'm very, like...
It feels intuitive, right?
Is Moon like Endgame?
No, definitely not.
So, apparently Moon is like Baby Steps.
There's other planets, dude.
And those planets have moons, too.
And...
There's a lot of planets.
Like, if you look in the...
in the game manual, there's like...
not a million, but there's a lot, okay?
And it's gonna probably take, uh...
a lot of the tech tree to even get there, I imagine.
I hope it does, at least.
I don't wanna end up with, like, half the tech tree and already able to explore everything.
I want it to be this way, where...
I guess the only time I can reach...
the hardest-to-reach planet or whatever is gonna be when I get the last tech, you know?
That would be like...
Oh!
Cinema.
Can we go to Titan?
Uh, it's a made-up solar system.
They don't have the same, uh...
planets and stuff, like the real one.
So there's a planet called Joule.
Duna.
There's Kerbin, of course.
There's a moon, which is called Moon.
There's also Minmus.
I'm trying to think of others.
Yeah, off the top, I can't remember more.
Have you ever wondered about why humans think that some things are cute and how evolution created feelings?
No, not really.
Maybe I've thought about it?
Briefly?
It is weird, though, isn't it?
Maybe it's like a defense mechanism.
If you're cute, other animals don't want to harm you.
They just want to smoosh you.
Actually, no, no.
Being cute is good for, like, mating, right?
I guess that would make sense.
Why are we talking about this?
Did you like the dark mode?
I gotta be honest.
After a while, I didn't even realize I had a different theme.
I totally forgot that was on.
So I guess it's fine.
Yeah.
I guess if I were to, you know, flip between the old theme, I'd probably like the new one more now because it's not as bright.
So yeah, I guess we keep the new theme.
I was gonna uninstall it, but I forgot.
So yeah, there you go.
Yeah, how was dark mode for you guys?
That's another question.
Did it help you guys a lot?
Because it is definitely bright in these dark scenes.
So if it helps you guys a lot, then we keep it for sure.
Please give side boosters a second chance.
Don't worry, I'm gonna...
Obviously, I'm gonna try again with different configurations.
That was just a one-off test.
Don't worry about it.
Of course we're gonna do it because it looks cool.
Are you talking about, like, an add-on, Yarku?
Oliver should watch Minecraft Live VOD.
Oh, there was another Minecraft Live?
Anything good?
Anything to get hyped about, or...
Also, Planet Shine mod?
I read online that you don't need it.
Because some other mod I have right now does the same thing.
So that's why I don't have that.
What shaders are you using?
I'm not using any shaders.
Well, I guess there's some shaders in this game, but are you talking about Minecraft?
I'm not using any shaders in Minecraft.
Autostrut is a setting.
It's not related to mods.
Oh, okay.
Autostrut.
That sounds to me like...
Instead of just walking normally down the street, you automatically start strutting, you know?
As you walk.
That's the first thing that comes to mind.
But, uh...
I will keep that in mind in case things start to wobble, like you said.
Autostrut to work.
Exactly.
You may try to create and fly a plane.
It's quite fun.
Yeah, I know you can make planes.
It's just that so far, I don't...
I don't want to.
Like, I don't want to fly a plane.
I want to make a rocket in the rocket game.
But at some point, I'm going to do it.
You know, it seems like I need to invest science into it, which is like a big...
No fucking way I'm doing that.
I'm putting my science into rockets for now.
Maybe when I get bored of rockets, I'll do planes.
Why fly low when you can fly high?
Exactly.
That's what I say.
Can a plane take you to the moon?
Actually, I guess, uh...
The space shuttle is half plane, half rocket.
Hey, it would be fun to make a space shuttle, actually.
Yeah.
Actually, that's kind of cool.
We should do that at some point.
Duckybird, exactly.
Did we say that at the same time?
I didn't even...
I didn't even read your message until after I said it.
Hey, Jen.
What's going on?
A plane can take you to the moon if you fly it wrong enough.
Is that because going to the moon is a euphemism for something else that I don't know about?
Holy shit.
27 months.
Thank you, Jen.
How's your day?
What's happening at the space center in real life?
Are you actually at a space center or, like, some space office?
How does that work?
You don't mind me asking.
An office in space.
I mean, that would be impressive.
I'm just imagining you have an office with the word space on it.
You go in and you're like, space.
I just woke up and said...
Dude, it is Saturday.
I actually didn't realize.
But I guess days are kind of flowing together for me lately.
I work in an office but I will occasionally get the opportunity to go to the pad in Florida.
That's cool!
Dude, I've always wanted to watch, like, a launch in real life.
Soon I'll do it.
I think I'll actually take a trip somewhere soon because I...
I almost never take trips, you know?
And it would be a...
a cool thing to do.
A good excuse to go to the States, you know?
To go watch a launch of something.
Maybe when Starship launches that's gonna be, like, a big, crazy event, right?
Imagine watching that.
Oh!
Starship is launching on Monday from Texas?
Oh, shit.
Maybe that's a little too close for me to plan around that.
But, I mean, apparently they're gonna start launching thousands of these.
You know?
So, I'll probably have the opportunity at some point.
I don't get why people like vacations that much.
I think it's because when you think of vacations, Kiroga, in the way that other people do as well, it's mostly related to traveling.
But in my mind, vacations can also be just staying at home and doing nothing.
You know?
To me, that's a vacation.
You inspired me to get back into this game?
Good!
Dude, this game is so much fun.
And, you know, I knew I was gonna like it before I went in because I played it before, right?
I got to the moon and all that, like I said.
But I am liking this so much more than I thought I would because of all the extra stuff they added since.
And, of course, the graphical mods take this from, I don't know, an already great game to a phenomenal game.
I love the career progression.
I love all the...
I love the contract system.
Still, I'm a little unsure about the reputation stuff, but like all of that is just so much fun.
I think if this was purely a sandbox game, I would not have had as much fun at all.
The career is what makes it for me.
It's also one of the things that I look most forward to in the future when I really want to get into Microsoft Flight Simulator 24.
because right now I'm like playing sometimes, you know, but I'm really waiting for a working, solid career mode.
And there is a career mode now in MSFS, but it's terrible, man.
Like, I'm waiting for that to be good.
And when it's there, I'm going to play the shit out of that game too.
I love the career in this game.
I meant that I don't like traveling too often.
Yeah, I totally get that.
We have a saying in Denmark called which means out is good, but home is best.
And that's how I feel.
Except it's like out is mediocre, home is phenomenal.
I have Yuki-stan.
I actually followed some updates lately after I got into all this.
Kit and Space Agency.
It looks incredible.
It's...
So apparently, this is the good news.
It's being made by some of the old devs from KSP.
And...
they're like making their own engine now.
Or at least they're not, you know, being restricted by Unity and stuff like that.
So they're free to basically go crazy.
And I think that's amazing.
So much potential there.
It's probably gonna be quite a bit of years though until that game is fully ready, you know?
But...
KSA is the real solo system.
But I read that they're not gonna make it a real solo system.
Like, they are planning on making it like a made-up version.
Smaller scale.
Except they don't quite know what yet.
Like, just that they are gonna do that.
But I guess it's cool as a starting point, right?
To have the real solo system.
You said you aren't gonna play vanilla, so do you wanna know about the huge...
Are you talking about World of Warcraft?
Minecraft?
Or what are you talking about?
Because when you say vanilla, I mean, that to me is World of Warcraft.
And since World of Warcraft is so relevant right now, what do you mean?
Oh, for Minecraft?
I mean...
Honestly, I'm not super excited to hear about a crazy...
update.
I mean, if I...
I think it would be cool to just play it at some point.
Just tell me, is it, like, amazing or not?
Is it something to get hyped about?
Or is it, like, meh?
On a scale of 1 to 10, how amazing is the update?
I guess.
Peak.
Really good.
10.
8.
Okay, well, that's pretty good.
That's pretty sick.
Janice being, uh...
the pessimist here.
Okay, 7.
But 7 is still okay.
They only announced it.
They haven't released.
Yeah, and when is this update coming that improves the graphics?
You know, the built-in shaders.
I feel like it's been ages since they announced that that was gonna come.
When is it coming?
2027 for sure.
Don't know when, though.
Yeah, I mean, nobody knows, I guess.
It's also so weird to me that they have two versions of Minecraft running.
Like, what?
Why is that even a thing?
Fucking pick one and focus on that.
It's nonsensical.
That, that, that...
I really don't understand that.
Because apparently that graphics update is already out for one version, but not the other.
Mojang has been silently making technical changes to the graphics system for a while now.
Every update, they're preparing.
Okay, well, it better be freaking amazing.
I mean...
It's probably gonna be good.
If they cooked on it that long, you know...
We're in Vulcan now.
Hey, really?
I mean, depending on the game, that's either a good or a bad thing.
But I guess since they're switching to Vulcan, it's gotta be good.
Like, they must have an idea of some...
performance increase or something.
Bedrock is the money slot version.
Java is the community-driven version.
Okay, but the thing I don't understand is time has once again or again and again proven that a game that has mod support is like a game that cannot die.
Why on earth would you not just support Java version?
Like, even from their perspective, okay, you want to add a store with all that stuff?
Fine.
Why not do it to Java?
It just doesn't make sense that they would separate it.
It's weird.
Java doesn't run everywhere?
Really?
I thought Java was one of the things that ran almost everywhere.
Is it, like, one of the most used languages, like, for anything?
It's meant to run on any platform, yet Minecraft Java only runs on PC.
C++ is notoriously hard to make multi-platform but works on any platform.
Oh.
Wait, wait, so if Java is meant to run on any platform, how come Minecraft written in Java only runs on PC?
Huh?
I'm not technical enough.
I don't know enough about C++ or Java for that.
Mojang wrote it badly.
Well, wouldn't it have been...
what's this guy?
Notch.
I don't know how much the codebase has changed since they took over.
But even...
Okay, let's just say...
Yeah, I don't know, man.
I guess I don't understand it.
Why they would do that.
Is there a stream preview for your next KSP stream?
What do you mean by that, J-Dong?
Also, when I read your name, I keep thinking of J-Dong from StarCraft.
Are you referencing that by any chance?
The Korean Cirque player J-Dong?
Or is that just a coincidence?
Isn't it pre-recorded?
I mean, yeah, yeah, it is.
I mean...
Oh, shit, I shouldn't say that.
I've not played Stellaris, but I've heard about it.
Can you play a little bit of the VOD for next stream?
Yeah, okay, okay, hold on.
I'll do it.
Fine.
But I can only play you the audio, okay?
Because the video got corrupted.
Okay, here we go.
Let me just go a little further in the VOD.
Well, that's not...
Okay, wait, that's not the right point.
Let me go a little further.
There it is!
We landed on the moon!
I can't believe...
Okay, that's the preview you get.
No more.
I closed it.
The VLC.
There we go.
It's gone.
Were the ads intention...
No, I...
No.
If there were ads, it's unintentional.
No, I just want to know when you stream, actually.
Oh, okay.
Jadong, I stream...
I almost hate answering this because I feel like I'm disappointing a lot of people with my answer.
I don't have a stream schedule.
I just stream whenever, you know?
But I guess around 3pm Central European Standard Time is usually the time I would stream if I do stream.
And sometimes I will put the stream in an event on Discord or on Twitch.
If I know I want to play tomorrow, for example, right?
Then I'll put it in there.
But yeah.
Will Galena make it to the moon, too?
I don't know.
We should strap it to a SpaceX rocket.
Are you unemployed enough to have a homelab?
Well, if you mean a homelab by...
I have a NAS with a bunch of storage in it for all the videos for YouTube.
And I do run some apps via that.
So I guess so.
But I wouldn't really call it a homelab.
That counts?
Okay, well, there it is.
I guess so.
I used to just have like three different hard drives of five terabytes.
You know, that you connect with a USB external drives.
And it was a freaking nightmare.
And I knew already, like, I knew of the problem people have had in the past trying to manage large amounts of data.
So I just...
I forced myself to immediately just invest in something that I knew was going to pay off later.
So I did not go too hard down the road of, you know, hoarding hard drives.
Just a little bit.
No, I didn't even read it as though it was meant in a mean way at all.
I thought this was a live stream.
I'm missing something about the preview bots.
Wait, preview bots?
Oh, are you referencing some kind of Twitch feature?
I feel like I've heard of that, but I don't know what that is.
No, but this is a live stream.
This is being sent live.
There's...
I don't know what preview bot is, actually.
Maybe it's just like a little video you can put up as a preview for what the channel is.
Like a channel trailer, maybe?
On a ring world, where would you set north on a compass?
Oh, that's...
I don't know.
Maybe just choose one direction around the ring and have that be north.
But how would that even work?
That's...
Yeah.
No, of course.
I would put it towards spawn.
What am I doing?
I would just let it point towards my spawn on that ring.
Easy.
Why does this background mess up my vision when I look away?
Because it's meant to do it.
I'm actually here to hypnotize all of you.
You are under my spell now.
You will follow my command.
You will go to the supermarket and buy healthy greens and make a very nice dinner filled with sustenance and you will after that go for a run.
How do you set north on a compass?
Let me just change the magnetic field real quick.
You don't know how to do that?
If you think about it...
Actually, don't think about it.
I'm having Fiskefli and Ruprød.
That is a wonderful combo.
Are you also having some lemon on top and some remoulade?
Otherwise, I will have to disown you.
But I assume you have that, of course.
No respectable Dane would eat that without remoulade.
I did play Yvonne Line at some point in the best me.
Not that much though.
It was kind of overwhelming, but the music stuck with me.
Really enjoyed the music.
And for some reason, if you listen to some of these tracks, it's actually quite similar in style to Kerbal Space Program.
It's actually quite striking, some of them.
I feel like they could have come out of this game.
My favorite Danish film?
Hmm.
Well, I really like Danish comedies.
So, Blinkende Løgter or Flickering Lights is one of my favorites.
I also really like Die Grønne Slagter and, of course, Ikina Spise de Hunden.
In China, they eat dogs.
What that movie's called.
Sprengfarlig Bombe is also one of my favorites.
There's just so many good scenes in that one.
Hunden skal døg.
Dude, I need to rewatch some of those.
I don't have a favorite, I don't think.
I think my favorite drama from Denmark maybe The Hunt with Mads Mikkelsen.
Man, even just thinking about that movie is sad as hell.
That movie will make you angry.
But it's a good one.
The Hunt.
Jakten in Danish.
Adam Zibler is also a good one.
Yes, Bastion.
True.
I thought the space track in KSP was very similar to a quick one before the Eternal Worm Devours Connecticut.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Is that a track that's called that?
But okay.
It's a song.
Okay, okay.
That's what I figured.
I was just like, what are you talking about?
Oliver, do you care about streaming popularity?
Because KSP is a little bit niche, I think.
Dude, with this game, I don't care how many are watching.
I'm playing it.
Actually, how many viewers did we have today?
What was like the max?
In case you know.
Right now we have 267.
Viewers.
500?
Well, that's not very niche, I would say.
That is pretty good.
4 to 500 is very good.
That's not bad at all.
Yeah.
I'm actually so happy people are enjoying this game.
Someone else in the comments on YouTube said that they started playing it too.
And someone in here.
because I was playing it.
And that makes me happy.
I want more people to play this.
You don't know how good this series has been.
Well, we just started Yogyestan.
It's gonna get better, trust me.
It's gonna be even better.
Yeah.
If the first bot got a crazy amount of views on YouTube, you know why?
Someone in the comments said, you should change the title to Astrophysicist plays and this will get a billion views.
And I did.
And I'm not sure if that's what did it, but it has gotten a lot of views now.
So there we go.
Maybe I should just call all my videos that.
Astrophysicist boils an egg.
Astrophysicist says hi to his cat.
It's marketing.
I guess so.
I mean, if you want to see Jackie, you can go to my other channel.
I have a couple videos of her.
It's called More Oliver.
It's actually right on the brink of being monetized.
So very soon I can monetize Jackie.
I will take photos of her and sell them online.
Why did you become an Astrophysicist?
Because I love it, man.
I love everything about space.
It's just so mysterious.
On a more practical note, it was because of my teacher in high school.
It was my teacher in high school called Carl Gustav.
Actually, his full name was Carl Gustav Blixen Finnecke, which is such an awesome Danish name.
He was really old and he had this funny accent.
And he was just so exciting and so exhilarating to listen to when he was explaining physics and stuff.
It wasn't even astronomy in general.
It was just physics.
You know?
And I was just completely consumed by it.
and then because I started getting consumed by it, I started, you know, consuming a bunch of pop literature or what's it called?
Popular science, you know?
Like Carl Sagan.
I read his books.
A candle, or science is a candle in the dark.
It's one of my favorites from him.
Cosmos, of course, the TV series.
Man, after watching that TV series, I, at that point, I knew I was gonna do something with space, you know?
I was just like, I was feeling it.
Man, those years were crazy.
I ate it all up, man.
They were like golden years of my life, really.
It was also the time in my life when I first really started watching movies.
And I had this whole backlog of movies all the way back from the 20s, you know?
All these bangers, like, I was just watching all of them.
IMDB Top 250?
Boy, I was eating that for lunch, breakfast, dinner.
I was consuming like a madman.
Those were the golden years, man.
I would lay out on the grass at night, you know, staring up at the sky, with my arms outstretched, feeling, you know, the surface of the earth.
It was almost like if you lay down like that and look up, that you could feel the rotation of the earth.
I mean, you couldn't really, but it felt like you could.
And it was just amazing.
I was also kind of a hoodlum before that, you know, I was kind of a troublemaker.
Got into a lot of trouble, got thrown out of a couple of schools because I was such a little bastard.
Science taught me right, man.
I was put on the right path.
It changed me.
Fuck yeah, man.
Science is truly a candle in the dark that will lead you out of despair.
Okay, sorry, I was waxing lyrical a little bit there.
Man,
what's your favorite plan in the real life solar system?
Saturn.
It's gotta be Saturn.
I just, I love the way it looks with the rings.
And the images we have from the Cassini probe are so unbelievably amazing that if you showed it to someone that doesn't know anything about this stuff, they wouldn't think it's real.
Like, it is unbelievable what those images show.
Just go on NASA's website and look at the Cassini archive of images.
It doesn't look real.
It is unbelievable how good those images are.
It's like, oh man, it's better than anything, any imagination could have cooked up, you know?
There's this incredible picture of Saturn where the sun is behind Saturn, you know, lighting up the rim of the planet and the rings and the alignment is just perfect.
So you get to see all kinds of things that you normally couldn't see, you know?
Because the sun's light is illuminating it while the sun is being obscured.
Some of those rings that we didn't even know existed can suddenly be seen in that photo.
And not only that, in that photo you can see Earth.
It's a tiny, tiny little dot.
You would think it was a speck of dust or something, but it's there, that's Earth, you know?
That photo is insane.
You gotta go look at those images.
I'm not even reading chat, I'm just fucking talking out loud to myself right now.
Sorry.
Have you seen the NASA website where they distribute pixels of space and you can earn a certificate from it?
No, I don't even know what that is.
Please check out JWST's image of Roe Opiochi.
It looks like a render.
Oh yeah?
I haven't actually caught up a lot with what JWST has been doing lately.
Well, I haven't been catching up with a lot of stuff.
Let me see this.
Adopt the pixel.
Claim your pixel on one of the first images from NASA's Nancy Grace Roman Space Telescope.
Wait, when is Roman going up?
Do we know that?
I mean, I guess we must know.
Maybe it's not precisely planned yet.
Interesting.
Oh, it's up there already?
I'm thinking about another one.
What is the telescope called?
You know, the follow-up to JWST, the one that's supposed to be like the next big one.
I forget the name of it.
You guys know?
What?
Did I really miss that?
Wait, there's no way I missed that.
Man, I must really be living in my own gaming world right now.
So, when did this launch?
Oh my god, it just fucking launched!
August 30th!
Well, there you go.
Shit.
Oh, I didn't see that, Zuko, sorry.
You just made your pixel.
I'm gonna see what that is all about.
I mean, I'm not really keeping myself up to date with a lot of this stuff anymore.
We heard of the game Observation.
I have not.
Maybe I have.
I'm unsure.
Guys, I need to eat.
I gotta go.
This was a great stream.
Thank you for hanging out.
Good talk afterwards, too.
We're gonna play more KSP.
Next up is Minecraft, though.
Maybe I'll have a little in-betweener stream with some deadlock.
So if any of you are up for doing some team games, you know, joining in, maybe some community games, let me know.
And go practice.
I'm gonna kick your ass.
No, I'm not.
I am.
Have a good one.
Bye-bye.